So, we met each other…
…when we were kids.
You knew who I was from the beginning, right?
Why didn't you tell me?
When you came to the library, I was really happy.
I was happy to see that the boy
from those days had come back to me.
But I realized soon enough that you didn't remember me.
Yet, you became friends with me again.
You treated me as kindly as a girl you had met for the first time.
You introduced me to many friends.
Then I got lost.
I couldn't decide if I wanted you
to remember or remain unaware…
…of what I was like back then.
Episode 13
Garden of Memories
“Those who pursue truth must not be arrogant.”
“Just because it can't be proven scientifically, you must not laugh at miracles.”
“You must not deny your eyes the beauty of this world.”
Those were my father's words.
Why was I named Kotomi?
Look around, Kotomi.
This world is composed of countless harps that cannot be seen by the naked eye.
Koto would be Japanese for harp.
Koto as in Kotomi?
The world is filled with harps,
and each one plays a different tune.
All those tunes intertwine with each other,
and a unique melody is born.
That's why the world is so beautiful.
It's Father's bad habit to try to speak eloquently.
The most important things are always very simple.
Your name is Kotomi.
Spelled with three cute hiragana.
You're Father and Mother's very, very precious treasure.
My house, the yard, Father, and Mother.
That's what my world was composed of.
Who are you?
Why are you here?
I was playing and wandered in here.
Who are you?
Kotomi.
You spell Kotomi with three hiragana.
When you call me, call me Kotomi-chan.
Oh my, we have a cute guest.
I was alone at school…
…because I read books my classmates wouldn't and thought of things they wouldn't.
But this boy, Okazaki Tomoya, seemed a little different from the boys I knew at my school.
A doll?
Yes. I want a doll of a bear for my birthday.
I see. Okay. I'll find you the cutest bear then!
To be honest, I didn't mind what I got as a present.
A book said girls usually wanted dolls, so I only copied that.
But…
What? Work?
It's a business trip that came up suddenly.
Both Father and Mother have to go.
But we promised! We promised that you'd both be here for my birthday!
Even Tomoya-kun will be here.
He said he'll come with his friends.
I have the food for the birthday party made already.
When Tomoya-kun and his friends come, eat it with them.
You two are liars!
I hate you both!
Kotomi.
I know! We'll pick up your bear on the trip.
A really big one.
We'll ship it to you, okay?
I don't need it!
I hate you both!
I hate you!
Nobody came on my birthday.
The housemaid got sick, too, so I was alone.
And, Tomoya-kun didn't show up, either.
May I come in?
I was told that I can't let people I don't know inside.
You haven't heard what happened to your father and mother yet?
He explained everything to me.
How the plane Father and Mother were on
malfunctioned in midair and sank into a distant ocean.
How a very important paper sank with them.
How there might be a spare copy in Father's study.
How important the paper was to the world, and therefore, how it had to be found.
Go home! Go home!
This person had to be a bad person.
He was here to take away
something important of Father's.
That was what I had thought.
I'll become a very good girl from now on.
I will never say anything selfish anymore.
I'll study a lot, too.
I'll read lots of books and become smart, too.
So dear god, I beg you.
Please bring Father and Mother back.
Please. Bring them back to me.
The crash occurred as they were flying to the United States for a special conference, having advanced their schedule.
A search party has been already sent out.
However, judging from the site of crash,
the chances of survival for the missing people are slim.
Father!
Mother, where are you?!
Mother!
I'll be a good girl!
I'll be a good girl…
Father's study was the last place I went into.
I was always told not to,
but that was the only place left to search.
I figured that had to be the important paper
the bad guy was talking about.
I believed that it was that which caused Father and Mother to disappear.
It was wrong for something like that to be so important.
I didn't care about the world.
All I wanted was Father and Mother.
Why did you do that?
I don't know.
Are these all articles about the crash?
I think I started this as a way of atoning for my sin.
I started to collect scraps of all the newspaper articles that talked about Father and Mother.
But that didn't feel enough to me, so I began
collecting pages from books that mentioned them.
Then, I studied a lot…
…because I wanted to follow
in the footsteps of Father and Mother.
Father and Mother were trying to express the foundation of this world using the most beautiful words.
It's something that must be told to everyone in the world.
It's something nobody else can copy.
Not even me.
But if I don't do it… god won't
forgive me for burning the paper.
Kotomi…
I don't want to experience anything that sad again.
I don't want to lose someone I love.
Please go home now.
I see, so you heard the story.
Sensei, is Kotomi present today?
She called saying she'll be absent for a while.
Okazaki-kun, do you know that
Ichinose-san has an offer to go study abroad?
Study abroad?
It's a program where a student with outstanding grades can study at a college in the US.
It's up to the individual to choose whether to come back to Japan after that or not.
Ichinose-san wasn't very enthusiastic about it couple days ago,
but today over the phone she said that she would accept the offer.
So Kotomi-chan has always remembered you.
Yeah. Although I only vaguely remember those times.
I'll visit Kotomi's place again.
Then I'll go, too.
You should go to class.
Pass along the details to Kyou and Fujibayashi for me.
Okazaki-san…
Kotomi…
Okazaki-san.
I told you to go to class.
The third period became a study hall.
I couldn't get it off my mind.
You're raking the yard?
Yeah, I wanted to do whatever I could.
Both Kyou-chan and Ryou-chan were saying the same thing.
“Let's do whatever we can.”
What are they planning to do?
That's a secret.
Give me a hint.
Birthday.
I see.
Um, did the hint make it too easy?
Kotomi's birthday is this coming Saturday, right?
Yes. Today's Tuesday, so in four days.
Pass the word to those two: “Let's do our best.”
I will.
But, I think Okazaki-san is the only person in the world who can bring Kotomi-chan back to school.
You're being overdramatic.
I am not!
It'll never get done at this rate.
I may have to get some tools together.
I'll continue tomorrow.
Good night, Kotomi.
Kotomi…
You're up there, right?
Oh yeah, this used to be a flowerbed.
It's gotten a little better, but I won't finish in time at the pace I'm going.
I have to do something about this, too.
I guess I have to get all the necessary tools.
This looks like more work than I'd expected.
Okazaki-san?
Hey.
What are you loitering around here for?
Shopping.
You're wealthier that I'd thought.
It's the money I had saved up
towards moving out of my house.
What are you guys doing?
Hey!
We meant to give it to Kotomi as a present.
We contacted the senpai who left the violin behind, and we officially received ownership.
Talking to Nishina-san, she said it should get properly tuned,
so we were on our way to an instrument shop.
Let me tell you, it's 100% the biker's fault.
If I'd had a metal pipe in my hand,
I would have smacked him along with his bike.
We're sorry.
This wouldn't have happened if we had been more careful.
You two are taking it too hard on yourselves.
It's about time you stop brooding over it.
She's right. Nothing will come from sitting here.
Let's head over to an instrument shop.
Being this damaged, it'd be cheaper to buy a new one rather than fixing it.
Hey, you're using our situation to your advantage and trying to make a sale off of it?
Stop, Kyou. That's too rude of you.
He's right, Onee-chan.
Um, it's something really important.
Can you do something about it?
He wouldn't accept it in the end.
He was definitely trying to take advantage of us.
But it's true that a new one would be cheaper.
It has to be this violin for Kotomi.
Let's try another shop.
We can't give up like this.
If you're so adamant about it…
But, even if it is repairable,
Saturday is an impossible date.
Then, how long will it take?
Well, it's a little tough to make a guess.
Somewhere between a month and half a year.
That's way too long!
Cut it down to two days, please.
You should stay quiet.
Also, when it comes back, there's no guarantee that it'll play with the sound it used to.
God, this is pissing me off.
There's nothing we can do.
We're lucky enough that he accepted it.
How much do you think the repair fee will cost?
You don't have to worry about that.
If it comes down to it, we'll collect money at school.
If you're the organizer, it might turn into blackmail rather than a collection.
It was so much fun up until a few days ago.
Why didn't things turn out well?
I wonder if Kotomi-chan is still at home.
Hey, you made quite a bit of progress.
You're amazing to have done all of this alone, Okazaki-san.
Not at all. I'm not sure if I'll make it for Saturday or not.
Kotomi! You're up there, right?!
Come out!
Kotomi!
Onee-chan, you shouldn't shout at her.
Yeah, you're disturbing the neighbors.
Okazaki-san, may we help, too?
Thanks, but it's already late.
If you arrive home late, your parents will be worried.
All right. See you later.
Please don't push yourself too hard, Okazaki-san.
I know. Once I get the tools together, I'll go home, too.
Good night, Okazaki-san.
Good night.
All right, I guess I'll do some more work.
What's likely buried here are my memories as a child.
Is Kotomi asleep?
I hope she's not having any nightmares.
Maybe what I'm doing right now is all a waste.
When that happens, what should I do?
When that happens, will I be able to bear it?
Okazaki-san!
We came back.
Just like Nagisa said, you're still working.
Please let us help you. Please.
Okay. Only thirty minutes, then.
Yes.
That's right. There's nothing to worry about.
I'm not alone.
Huh?
What's wrong?
I thought I just saw the curtain move.
Let's keep working.
Yeah.
To be Continued
Preview
Day before yesterday I saw a rabbit,
and yesterday a deer,
and today, you.
I always remembered the boy who wandered into the yard.
I really, really liked that boy.
He was my only friend…
…so I kept waiting for him.
Episode 14