What are these lights?
I'm sure that I've never known a view such as this.
Do you find the lights strange?
What about the sky?
What about the ground?
Just these lights?
Why would that be?
To her, someone who has been here her entire life, these lights are natural.
“These must be shadows!” is what I thought.
But a shadow always comes with an object that causes it.
If so, then where would that be?
In other words,
for you to find this strange, there must be
some other scene that you do  find familiar.
I dig through my memories.
I was in a different world a long time ago…
or perhaps the distant future.
I still retain the memory that I was once there.
Okazaki-san, good morning.
Nagisa, what are you doing?
You'll be late.
I caught a glance of you, so I was waiting for you.
I shouldn't have?
No, it's fine, but…
Then let's go.
Yes!
We still can't get new members, huh?
You're right.
Maybe I'll go ask her.
Her?
Tomoya, move!
Tomoya!
Okazaki-san, are you all right?!
Please get a hold of yourself!
Hey, Tomoya-kun.
Okazaki-san?
Looks like he's fine.
Bye.
You're just going to leave?!
I'm joking with you.
Nagisa, did you get hurt at all?
No, I was fine.
I see.
What?
Awfully close now, aren't you?
Calling her by her first name.
Are you two dating now?
Have you kissed already?
Of course not!
I-I'm only having Okazaki-san help me reestablish the club.
We're not dating!
Okay. I'll leave it at that.
See you later.
Okazaki-san, are you really not hurt?
When did I start calling you by your first name?
Um…
I almost remembered something just now.
Me too.
Something very warm…
…nostalgic…
…and sad.
Let's get going, Nagisa.
Yes, Okazaki-san.
Episode 10
The Genius Girl's Challenge
Recruiting members for the drama club?
Yeah, there won't be anything fun even if you tag along.
Don't be such a stranger. I want to help Nagisa-chan, too.
Do you seriously like Nagisa?
Of course!
I've never loved anyone so seriously before.
In the library up ahead, there's a mysterious and
beautiful girl who is always reading difficult books.
If you talk to her, she occasionally gives you food.
Really cute, innocent, smart,
and it looks like she doesn't have a boyfriend.
Please introduce me to her!
I think she's there right now.
Go check her out.
All right!
Library
What is he doing in there?
I was com—
—pletely ignored!
That was a long pause.
She won't react to small or sweet talk.
It pissed me off, so I threw books everywhere and knocked bookshelves over, but she still ignored me.
Who the hell is she?
She's Ichinose Kotomi. You know the name, right?
Ichinose Kotomi…
That famous genius girl…
So basically she lives in a different world.
That was a waste of time.
A person in a different world, huh?
Hey, Kotomi.
Kotomi-chan.
Tomoya-kun.
Hello.
Tomoya-kun. You can't make a mess like this.
You never change, do you?
The drama club?
I told you about it before.
We're recruiting members.
Do you want to go see the club president after school?
She won't bully me?
That's one thing that'll never happen, so don't worry.
Um…
She's the new member candidate.
Come on, introduce yourself.
Hello, Tomoya-kun
Not to me!
Say your name first.
Um…
Kotomi.
You spell Kotomi with three hiragana.
When you speak to me, call me Kotomi-chan.
I'm Nagisa, spelled with one kanji character.
People refer to me differently though…
Nagisa-chan.
Yes!
Can't you guys talk about anything other than your names?
My last name is Ichinose.
Mine's Furukawa.
I'm in Class A.
I'm in Class B.
Type A blood.
I'm type A, too.
Pork cutlet sandwich.
Anpan.
Elephant.
Kitty.
Okay, stop!
It's no longer making sense.
Despite her appearance, she's really smart,
so she doesn't need to study for entrance exams.
She likes books, so she has a good vocabulary.
So, as a candidate for new member, she's a perfect…
Hey, what are you doing?
Are you all right?
Is this Tamatebako?
Tamatebako: A box from the story Urashima Tarou with smoke inside that ages those who get covered by it.
No, it's not.
Nagisa, you say something to her, too.
Um…
I'm jealous of how beautiful your hair is.
No! I'm telling you to talk her into joining the drama club!
You practiced the speech, remember?
Say things like, “Let's shed the tears of youth together”, or something.
Do I have to cry?
When the scene requires it,
then there are times you have to.
I don't want to cry.
Still when you have to, you have to.
Nagisa-chan, are you a bully?
No. I'm not a bully.
It's the Big Dango Family.
Do you like the Big Dango Family?
Yup.
I love it.
I'll walk Kotomi back today.
Yes. I'll see you tomorrow.
Today, I was a little scared.
I'm always like that when I talk to a person I've just met.
But Nagisa-chan was kind.
If you're so scared of others,
why were you able to talk with me so easily?
Nagisa-chan is a very kind person.
Her Big Dango Family pictures were good, too.
I'll just leave it at that.
Is Nagisa-chan your girlfriend?
No!
Why did both you and Kyou ask that?
Kyou?
The class representative of Class E and a vicious little girl.
Oh, that's right, Tomoya-kun.
There's a place I want to stop by.
You really take everything at your own pace, don't you?
You really like books, huh?
I can't become a well-established person if I don't study a lot.
You think so?
Stop it, you idiot.
What's wrong, Tomoya-kun?
Don't give me that!
No matter how much you like books,
you can't cut those in the library or bookstores.
If you must, copy what you need onto a piece of paper…
Actually, you might get yelled at for that, too.
You think so?
You really should socialize with others more.
Will she bully me? Will she bully me?
She won't, so introduce yourself.
Hello, Tomoya-kun
Okay, that was good practice. Now for the real thing!
So? What am I supposed to do?
Come on, Kotomi.
Um…
Kotomi.
You spell Kotomi with three hiragana.
When you speak to me, call me Kotomi-chan.
Huh?
Is she a bully?
She's the famous genius girl, right?
Why is she hanging out with a bum like you?
Who are you calling a bum?!
Will she bully me? Will she bully me?
You don't have to be so frightened.
She's just like this.
You've got lots of friends, right?
I was wondering if you can be friends.
Isn't there something strange about becoming friends because you're asked?
Friends aren't given; you're supposed to make them.
Of all the times for her to spit out common sense.
Besides, why are you taking care of her?
What happened to helping Nagisa?
That is still in progress.
Apparently, I'm good at taking care of others.
So yet another rival appears against her.
Did you say something?
Nothing.
Bye. I've got things to do.
Oh, right.
My name's Kyou.
Fujibayashi Kyou.
Bye.
Okay, I admit that she was a difficult one to approach.
But you have problems, too.
Instead of just reading books,
you should learn how to communicate with others.
Like making jokes and jabbing at them.
Jokes and jabs?
We'll practice it a little at a time.
Your goal is to make a hundred friends.
A hundred friends? Tomoya-kun, that's amazing!
Sorry, I don't have that many friends.
No, you need to jab me back,
not put a question mark on your face.
Jab…
What the heck. I can't get along with you.
Bye now.
Looks like we have a lot of work to do.
Be her friend?
Yeah, we're looking to make her friends.
Come on, introduce yourself.
Hello, Tomoya-kun
That's getting old.
Um, how are you two related?
Think of us as class ditching buddies.
Although, I'm a delinquent while she's a genius.
Um, if you don't mind, may I read your fortune?
That's perfect for a conversation topic.
Go ahead.
Will she bully me?
Don't ask me.
I'll read your fortune for today.
Please pick any three cards you like.
May I see them please.
I don't think you can make friends.
Don't deny my efforts like that!
Wait, hold on, stop!
Nothing will change if you run away.
You must face reality.
Ryou-chan is a bully?
I-I don't think I am.
You just were.
You declared that she won't make any friends.
But there are times when fortune telling fails.
Even if there's a bad reading, the future should depend on the individual and their surroundings.
Does it work like that?
Yes. Since I think you're a fun person, too.
Then you'll be her friend?
Yes, if that's okay with you.
How she differs from her vicious sister really helps.
Ryou-chan wasn't all that scary.
If we weren't talking to Fujibayashi,
you would have weirded the person away.
So first, you have to learn the basics. How to make an introduction:
Hello. Nice to meet you.
My name is Ichinose Kotomi. A senior in Class A.
My hobby is reading books.
I would be happy if you would become my friend.
Good. We'll practice that during the next break.
Is there anyone good to practice on…
What are you doing, Tomoyo?
A bear…
You're not on patrol, right?
Maintenance check on the suit?
Oh yeah. Introduce yourself to her.
Um…
Hello. Nice to meet you.
My name is Ichinose Kotomi. A senior in Class A.
My hobby is reading books.
I would be happy if you would become my friend.
Looks like she likes you.
It's so fluffy.
Do you, y'know, like stuffed bears?
Yup.
I love them.
Hey, Okazaki. So that's where you were!
Let's eat lunch—
You're the bear that kicked me the other day!
Don't move from there! I'll get my rezombie on you!
Rezombie?
He always gets a failing grade in English.
A wonderful kick as usual.
There we go.
What's this? Ditching class with a girl today?
I am, but she's a true genius, so she's exempt from classes.
Hello. Nice to meet you.
My name is Ichinose Kotomi. A senior in Class A.
My hobby is reading books.
I would be happy if you would become my friend.
I see. So you're the Ichinoses' Kotomi-chan.
You know her?
I'm sure a lot of those that
live in this city would know her.
After all, her parents are amazing scholars.
Scholars?
Are your parents college professors or something?
Um…
Yes…
I see. You're made differently from me at the genetic level.
Ah, there you are!
See, I won't bully you.
Good girl. Good girl.
I thought you don't become friends because you're asked to.
You're right. That's why I  approached her.
But we don't know each other well yet.
If we go hang out together,
I'm sure we'll get to know each other better.
With that said, don't you think this is your chance to show how dependable you are?
Are you planning on mooching off of me?
I'll talk to Ryou about it, too,
so take us somewhere interesting later.
This  is the interesting place?
Isn't it a nice place?
Listen! I was looking forward to karaoke or arcades or fast food restaurants or stuff like that!
Aren't we being a bother by
imposing on this many people?
No, I'm happy.
It's rare for this room to become so lively.
I created the opportunity for you, so use it.
You had better take a step forward.
Um…
Hello. Nice to meet you.
My name is Ichinose Kotomi. A senior in Class A.
My hobby is reading books.
I would be happy if you would become my friends.
My name is Furukawa Nagisa. A senior in Class B.
My hobby is acting.
I would be happy if you would become my friends.
My name is Fujibayashi Ryou. A senior in Class D.
My hobby is fortune telling.
I would be happy if you would become my friends.
My name is Fujibayashi Kyou. A senior in Class E.
My hobby is bullying weaklings.
I would be happy if you would become my friends.
Whose hobby did you say it was to pick on weaklings?
Okazaki-san!
Did you see that jab, Kotomi?
It's this timing that you have to master.
U-Um…
I'm actually very strong, so I don't want you to bully me.
I can't get along with you…
This isn't exactly what I had in mind…
Why don't you all just join the drama club?
With this number of people, it would
be enough to convince the student council.
My apologies to the president, but I'll pass on that.
Both Ryou and I don't have any intention of acting.
But please come visit often as you like.
Simply seeing the timing of when
a jab should happen is a learning experience.
I'll practice a lot, and maybe then
I'll be able to get a good jab in, too.
You're admirable, Kotomi-chan.
I'll cheer you on, so good luck.
Please let me join in, too.
Let the three of us work together, then!
Yup.
Yes.
A really strange group has formed.
Let's work hard.
You're part of it.
Oh well.
She looks like she's enjoying herself.
Okazaki-san's jabs are always very harsh.
So I sometimes get—
Is something wrong, Kotomi-chan?
Hey, Kotomi.
Music Room
Um, is there something you need?
Hey, Kotomi.
What's wrong?
I'm sorry. Was it noisy?
No, it wasn't bothering us.
Kotomi-chan, what's the matter?
A violin…
Would you like to play it?
I can?
Sure.
Kotomi, you can play the violin?
Kotomi! Stop, stop!
You're putting too much strength into it!
You need to relax more!
She doesn't hear us!
So nice.
Tomoya… What's wrong with her?
Don't ask me…
To be Continued
Preview
I was about to fall into an eternal sleep from the shock!
What the heck?
Let's see…
Okay. The day after tomorrow, on Monday, we'll hold your violin recital.
What the heck?
Are you sure? Isn't Kotomi's violin…
It'll be fine. She's improved a lot.
What the heck?
Therefore…
We've been left alone.
Episode 11
An After School Rhapsody
What should we do?
I'm tired, so I'm going to sleep.
What the heck?