Okazaki-san.
What’s wrong?
I didn’t see you around, so I decided to go looking.
Do you practice out here every night?
Only sometimes.
Being out here, I won’t bother the neighbors if I’m too loud.
You should be more careful.
It’s dangerous for you to
be alone outside this late at night.
It’s all right.
It’s right in front of my house,
so Dad will come running if I call out.
It worries me since you look slow.
Do I look like I’m slow?
You never thought you were?
This is a shock.
You shouldn’t get down so easily.
I’m just joking with you.
I’m used to you being mean to me.
Don’t get used to something like that.
I’m sorry about having such a dirty mouth.
No, it’s fine. You wouldn’t be Okazaki-san any other way.
Yeah.
Okay.
Have you remembered anything about the play you want to perform?
I still can’t remember the title,
but it’s a story I was told when I was little.
How does it go?
It’s a story about a girl left all alone in a world that ended.
It’s a very, very sad…
…story about a winter fantasia.
It’s done.
I’m sorry.
A girl in a world that ended.
I feel like I’ve seen something like that.
Though, I don’t know when or where I saw it.
But I’m sure…
So I’ve been a lead weight on Furukawa Bread?!
I love them!
Episode 20
Secret Past
Damn it, I messed up.
What happened this time?
I was recommending Sanae’s bread to a customer, but he said it’s so gross that it’s inedible.
Sanae overheard that.
It’s called “rainbow bread”.
Rainbow to you!
That made absolutely no sense.
A girl in a world that ended…
Nope, doesn’t ring a bell.
Do you think it might be some memory from the past?
Have you ever read her a book or told a story like that?
No, I don’t recall anything like that.
Ask Sanae about it.
I see…
All right then.
Hey, brat.
I don’t know what you’re trying to find out.
But, even if you do, don’t tell Nagisa about it.
Come tell me first.
Why?
‘Cause I said so.
Got it?
No, I don’t remember anything like that either.
Can you give it some thought?
If it wasn’t a book, could it have been a
television show that you watched with her?
Do you know how the story ends?
She said it was a sad story,
so it probably wasn’t a happy ending.
A sad story…
Nothing comes to mind.
I’m not very good with sad stories to begin with,
so I don’t think I’ve ever told
something like that to Nagisa.
I see.
Is this something important?
Yes, sort of.
It’s…
Something important.
Yeah, I feel like it’s something important.
It’s possible that we might have forgotten about it, and the book you’re talking about is stored somewhere in the house.
How about searching for it?
Thank you very much. I’ll do that.
I don’t think you’d find it at this school.
We don’t have many picture books or children’s books.
I guess that’s to be expected of a high school library.
We do have good resources for plays performed at high schools.
Would those help?
Thanks, but apparently it’s not a theatrical play.
I see.
Never mind that, Yukine-chan.
If there are charms that’ll tell me which girls like me, can you teach them to me?
We’re having a serious conversation, you know?!
Yes, I do have one.
Seriously?!
Tada.
First make a heart using your thumbs and index fingers.
Then chant, “To love, to be loved,
to dump, to be dumped,” three times.
To love, to be loved, to dump, to be dumped.
What’s next?
Walk around the school once; the first girl who talks to you is the girl who is interested in you.
Okay! I’m off!
Hey.
Yes?
Do girls prefer getting asked out?
Are you talking about Furukawa-san?
I never mentioned her name.
Of course, hearing “I love you” from
the person they love makes girls happy.
But… the timing is more important.
If you’re too forceful or sudden in
your approach, it may push her away.
That’s how it works?
So hot…
How did it go?
How many laps did you do?
And no one talked to you?
Leave me alone.
I’ll get a cup of water for you.
I think Okazaki-san should try it next.
I’m doing it, too?
Make the heart with your fingers.
I’m not really interested in it.
Sunohara, you’re in the way.
I’m not sure why, but I feel like I’d have something completely opposite of a romantic relationship with her.
A hungry bear is roaming around here right now.
So you must keep running quietly while playing dead.
As if you’re a zombie.
That was a close call.
Okazaki-san.
I came looking for you since you’re late.
What were you doing?
No, um…
…to dump, to be dumped.
Out you go now.
The first girl who talks to you
is the one that cares about you.
What’s the matter?
N-Nothing.
Everyone’s gathered now.
It’s a story I heard long ago.
I don’t remember if I read it in a picture book or if someone told it to me.
The girl was the only person in the entire world.
It was very sad and very lonely for her,
so she decided to make a friend.
It was a doll made by putting together pieces of junk.
The doll started to move, responding to the girl’s wishes.
So then, the girl was no longer lonely.
The end.
Yes, I do know this story.
Look at this!
I found something incredible!
You found it?!
Family Welfare
I used to go to elementary school with this on my bag.
Dango, dango, dango, dango. Dango—
You should have graduated from that, too.
Who’s the one singing such
an embarrassing song inside the shed?
Your daughter.
We’re looking for the picture books that
I read when I was little and stuff like that.
You won’t find any picture books in here.
But we might find some if we look for them.
I said that there’s nothing here.
Just go back to your room and flirt with
each other like all the other teenagers do.
Wait.
What the heck am I encouraging them to do?!
Don’t get all excited by yourself.
Shut up and just get out already!
Come on.
What do you want with me?
Don’t tell Nagisa what I’m about to tell you.
Don’t tell Sanae that we had
this secret conversation, either.
I don’t want it coming up again.
Okay.
Tea would be nice right now.
Hey, Sanae! Make us some tea!
Okay!
Hey, I just said it’s a secret from Sanae, too!
What kind of brain do you have?
That was close.
Now we’re fine.
You see, brat—
Here’s your tea.
Ah, thank you.
Okazaki-san, here you go.
Thank you.
Yup. Japanese people have to drink tea.
Let me remind you again: don’t repeat what I’m about to say to Nagisa or Sanae.
Is there something regarding me?
‘The hell?! She’s right next to me?!
I’ll leave once you’re done drinking, so don’t worry.
Brat, chug it down!
You’re not doing this on purpose, are you?
We can finally settle down and talk.
You’re the one making this all complicated.
Did you find what you were looking for?
No, not yet.
I see. Well I don’t care too much about that.
I don’t care about the potty-chair Nagisa used when she was little.
I don’t care about that, either.
You guys were frantically looking for it, though!
We weren’t looking for a potty-chair! We’re looking for a picture book!
Both of you. Night has fallen, so please keep it down.
Whatever. We’ll set the potty-chair aside for now.
I said the potty-chair has nothing to do with this.
Shut your mouth!
Then we’ll make this conversation’s codename “potty-chair”.
I don’t care about it anymore.
Let’s continue.
I don’t really care about what you’re looking for.
But I don’t want you accidently finding a certain other thing.
A certain other thing?
You want to know?
If you don’t want to talk about it,
then I don’t need to know about it.
I’ll tell you.
I don’t want you to get the idea that I have ten thousand hidden porno mags.
I never had that idea!
Listen. What’s stored in that shed is my and Sanae’s past.
Like old pictures and diaries.
What’s in there is the us of the past when we were still chasing our dreams.
You don’t want that found?
Yeah.
When Nagisa was little, something
happened which she almost died from.
She had a close brush with death.
It was more than ten years ago.
Sanae was working as a middle school teacher.
Those were busy days, since I was
finally able to pursue what I wanted to do.
What was it that you wanted to do?
That doesn’t matter right now.
What matters is that we were absorbed within our own worlds, since we had finally been given the chance.
Therefore, we couldn’t make
much time to be with Nagisa.
One day, Nagisa got a fever.
It was a cold, snowy day.
The nursery school was closed.
We couldn’t find anyone who could come over to help.
But those were busy days for both Sanae and me,
so we couldn’t skip a day of work.
Her fever was going down, and I could
come home as soon as I finished with my work.
It was only for a span of two hours.
But…
Nagisa was outside, waiting for us.
I thought it was a punishment from God.
I thought he was taking Nagisa away from us for leaving our daughter alone in order to pursue our careers.
I’m sure there are many people who can handle chasing their dreams and raising their kids.
But we couldn’t.
When Nagisa opened her eyes, we made a vow.
We swore that we’d always be with her.
We changed occupations after that.
The reason we chose a bakery was because
Sanae said she was confident at baking bread.
But you’ve seen the results of when she bakes.
So I had to learn everything from scratch.
I had to go into quite a bit of debt, too,
so those were rough days.
But it was still kinda fun.
And you don’t want Nagisa finding that out?
Because of what Nagisa would probably think.
That because of her, Sanae and I
had to give up on our dreams.
I can’t say for sure,
but when I was little, it felt like I did something really bad to Dad and Mom.
Nagisa’s starting to notice.
That’s why we hid all the memories in the shed.
We could have burned them,
but Sanae probably would have cried.
Wouldn’t it be better to tell Nagisa about it?
If you explain it clearly, I think that
she would have the strength to accept it.
Maybe, but regardless, she’ll probably be shocked if I suddenly slam it in her face.
That’s why I’m trying to find the right time to tell her.
The truth is always harsh at first.
Out of the blue, but…
…here’s a question!
There’s something I’ve been planning for tomorrow.
What could it be?
1: Picnic.
2: Twitch.
3: Picric Acid.
I don’t know what the last choice is.
There is a chemical called picric acid.
It’s an aromatic, nitrous compound.
I see. I learned something new.
So, Nagisa, which one’s the answer?
Yes! 1: Picnic!
Wrong. The correct answer is 2: Twitch.
Therefore, tomorrow, we’ll all twitch together.
Nagisa, let’s go on a picnic together, then.
Yes.
Wait! Don’t leave me out!
Okazaki-san. Can I forget about acting tomorrow and enjoy myself?
Akio-san, you can enjoy twitching alone.
Sanae, I love you.
Sure. You have to take time to recover, too.
Yes, I love you, too.
Yes.
Okazaki-san, if you have something you like, let me know.
I’ll pack it in the bento.
Yes.
I want to eat an apple with rabbit ears.
Dad, you can’t start requesting already!
I request hamburger!
Then I’ll request shrimp tenpura.
Are normal families supposed to be like that?
I probably shouldn’t go.
I wonder what Pop’s doing.
Someone’s here!
Don’t be surprised now.
Okazaki. Why are you here?
No real reason.
Why are you up so early?
I’m going to bed now.
Picnic, huh?
You’re right; it’s not really for you.
You think so, too? If I’m there,
I’ll probably ruin their family trip.
But if you do something like this,
wouldn’t Nagisa-chan be shocked?
I did leave a note saying,
”I have something to do, so please go without me.”
Knowing Nagisa-chan, she’ll probably get all worried.
Like, “Maybe my home isn’t comfortable for him.”
I’m sure she won’t think that just from me not going on a picnic.
Nagisa-chan always lacks confidence in many things.
Always unsure.
That’s how she appears to me.
She said she was getting confident in herself just the other day.
That’s because you’re with her though, right?
Since you’re there to encourage and yell at her, she can try lots of things and gain confidence, too.
That’s a good thing.
That’s my point.
Think about it.
She gained confidence because of you.
But if you turn away from her, what will happen to all the confidence she’s built up?
Nagisa-chan doesn’t have a clear
understanding of how you see her.
Your indecisive attitude has trapped Nagisa-chan.
You ran away from your house,
and now you’re running away from hers, too.
It’s only a bother to me for you to take refuge here.
But, if you resist so strongly,
then I’ll go on the picnic in your place.
Maybe love will bloom
between us with this as the trigger.
I’m going home.
Sorry I bothered you.
I’m done.
Nagisa!
Okazaki-san.
I’ve been searching for you.
Didn’t you read my letter?
No, I don’t know anything about it.
Thank goodness, Okazaki-san. We were waiting for you.
Um, didn’t you see my letter?
I ate it as a side for my breakfast.
Old man…
Given the time now, we can’t travel someplace anymore.
I’m sorry.
I apolo—
We couldn’t leave because of you.
So take responsibility and play with us.
Eh?
I’m getting some big hits today.
Did you see that, Sanae?
Yes. I saw it clearly.
You’ve fallen in love with me again, haven’t you?
Yes.
You’re wonderful, Akio-san.
Aren’t I?
We didn’t have to go and lay the sheet, did we?
Okazaki-san.
I helped making this bento, too.
Please have some.
Yeah.
It’s good.
I’m glad to hear that.
Brat!
You’re up to bat!
Hurry up and get in the batter’s box.
All right!
Well, I’m off.
Yes. Off you go.
Can I swing the bat with my shoulder?
All right! Good one, brat!
Did you see that, Nagisa?!
Yes, I saw it clearly!
You fell in love with him again, didn’t you?
Yes—
Dad?!
Damn it! So she is in love with him?!
Hey, Nagisa! You’re up next!
I’m batting, too?
Get moving!
Let’s go, Onee-chan!
You can do it, Nagisa.
Good job, Nagisa!
Yes.
Start running, Nagisa!
Yes!
To be Continued
Preview
This is a world that has ended.
A world where no one exists aside from myself.
It’s not about being alone at school or home,
but being alone in the world.
It’s a very sad thing, isn’t it?
Episode 21
In Preparation for the School Festival
Yes, it’s a very sad thing.