Go to Ibuki-sensei's house?
Yeah.
We'll meet her in person and ask.
Then we'll know for sure
if she's Ibuki-sensei's sister or not.
You'll come with us, won't you?
Fuuko will wait here.
Why? We'll get things done faster if you meet her, too.
She's suspicious.
Why doesn't she want to come with us?
There might be a reason.
How can we believe her?
We don't know if she's a ghost or a wandering phantom,
but it's ridiculous to think that
she's a spirit and her body's at a hospital.
She's human no matter how you look at her.
Well that's…
I'm sure there's something.
Maybe like a reason that forces her to say she's Ibuki Fuuko.
Or maybe she believes she's Ibuki Fuuko for some reason.
What kind of reason could that be?
How would I know?
Episode 5
A Scene with a Sculpture
Sensei!
Good evening. I'm Furukawa.
Nagisa-chan. How unexpected of you to visit.
Oh.
Hey, you're the person that came to buy bread.
Okazaki-san, you know Ibuki-sensei?
I gave her Sanae-san's bread once
when there wasn't anyone in your store.
So is he your boyfriend?
No!
No hesitation.
Ah, I didn't mean that I don't like you…
Um… I'm sure there's a person better suited for you…
Do you already have someone you're in a relationship with?
No, I don't have anyone like that.
You don't?
Looks like you have a good chance, Nagisa-chan.
P-Please pretend you didn't hear what I just said.
Nagisa-chan's cute, isn't she?
Well, ah….
Right! Sensei! Congratulations on getting engaged!
I heard that there's a certain Yuusuke-san that you'll be marrying soon.
So we're here to congratulate you.
Who did you hear that from?
His name, too.
I didn't tell this to anyone but my little sister.
You're sure? You've only told your little sister?
Yes, to my sister who's in a deep, long sleep.
Nagisa-chan. You know how
my sister, Fuuko, is sleeping, right?
Yes.
Even though she's asleep, I talk to her often.
I've told her about my marriage, too.
But no one else.
Um…
We heard a rumor about it at school.
Maybe someone who saw you walking
with your boyfriend embellished the story.
I see. Then that makes sense.
How is your sister doing?
I went to check up on her a while ago.
Her complexion looked better than other days.
To be honest, I'm not sure if I'll get married or not.
Given the situation my sister is in,
I can't make the decision if I should get married and just have my own happiness.
What's going on?
I almost couldn't stop myself from telling her…
…that Fuuko-chan is at school right now.
You should have.
Everything's solved by having the two of them meet.
But I feel this is something
I shouldn't talk about so carelessly.
Fuuko-chan was against it, too.
Furukawa, do you really believe that?
That she's a ghost or spirit or something like that?
If it's about the marriage,
maybe she overheard the guy talking about it.
I know it is strange, but I don't think Fuuko-chan is lying.
I don't know why, but…
Fuuko-chan is making those sculptures to get people to celebrate her sister's marriage, right?
Hey, don't cry.
Yes, I won't cry.
Instead…
I want to help her!
Help her with what she's trying to accomplish!
You get really worked up if it's for others, huh?
What are you going to do about the drama club?
That's also important, but I can't leave
Fuuko-chan alone in a state like that.
I'm sorry. I know you've helped me a lot, but…
I'll tag along.
Fuuko's situation does bother me, too.
I've got nothing better to do, anyway.
Okazaki-san…
Are you sure Fuuko can impose upon you like this?
I can't let you sleep at school.
Your parents know of Ibuki-sensei, right?
Yes, since she comes often to buy bread.
Then we should hide her last name.
Come up with something, okay?
Okay.
So basically,
you want us to let her stay here for a while.
We have no problem with it, but what about your family?
Well, they're horrible parents.
They left her behind and went away on a vacation.
Right?
What's your last name, Fuuko-chan?
It's Isogai!
She sure picked a unique one.
Isogai Fuuko-chan?
Isogai-san is our neighbor, right?
You idiot!
Okazaki-san!
She took the next-door neighbor's last name!
Is she the neighbor's relative or something?
Not at all! It's a complete coincidence!
I see. So it's a coincidence.
I think we could have fooled them even if we had said, “Ibuki”.
Um.
Fuuko will be in your care.
Hey, she knows her manners.
We look forward to getting to know you, as well.
Hey!
I won't be so forgiving if it happens again!
We're sorry!
They went to peep on the girl's dormitory again.
They want your attention.
Be a little more strict and I bet they'll stop being stupid.
Is it something like that?
A slap isn't enough.
I think a joint lock would be enough against them even with a woman's strength.
I don't like violence, though.
Oh, Okazaki. You're here?
Hey, peeping tom.
Huh?
Hold him.
Divine punishment!
My arm hurts.
Now I can't go mess with the student council.
Regarding the drama club,
we won't be doing anything for a while.
We have something else to do now.
Something else to do?
Yeah. Babysitting a ghost girl.
Not that I believe she's a ghost.
Huh? Ghost?
Fuuko bothers me, but I'm worried about Furukawa, too.
So I'll be helping out and keeping an eye on them for a while.
Therefore, give me tea.
That doesn't follow!
Hello!
I'm coming up.
Hello.
What the hell is this?!
I'm bleeding!
What are you doing so early in the morning?
Oh, it's Okazaki-san.
Good morning, Okazaki-san.
Have you all been carving these since last night?
Yes, we're helping Fuuko-chan.
Excuse me!
Hey, you have a customer.
You go.
What?
The shop.
That's not something you should be asking your daughter's friend to do!
He's right, Akio-san.
That's right, Sanae-san. Tell him.
We can carve these while minding the store.
If Sanae says she loves me that much, then fine!
No one said that!
All right, time for labor.
Yes.
I'll get ready for school, too.
When you see all of them together, the floor looks like a starry sky.
Why?
Well, these are stars, right?
No, they're starfish.
Come again?
They're starfish.
You were making starfish the entire time?
Of course. Fuuko doesn't understand why Fuuko would have to carve stars.
That doesn't make any sense.
Starfish make even less sense!
Seeing them all together makes them very cute.
Starfish.
Did she tell you these were starfish?
No, that's what I thought they were from the beginning.
How can you tell?
And do you think starfish are cute, too?
They are, since Fuuko-chan made them.
I don't care anymore.
Please.
We managed to give out a lot.
We can give out a lot thanks to you two helping.
Wouldn't you rather meet
your sister than be doing this?
Fuuko does want to meet her,
but Fuuko wonders if she'll hear Fuuko.
What do you mean?
Fuuko thinks Fuuko is here doing this
because Fuuko can't see or talk to her.
Because there isn't anything else Fuuko can do.
Um, Fuuko-chan. What does your sister call you?
Fuu-chan.
Then can I call you that, too?
Yes.
Can I call you that, too?
That'd be horrible!
Why?!
It just is!
Why you…
Miyazawa, you here?
Welcome.
And this is?
Um, please take this.
What?
A present for you.
Thank you very much.
I see. So she's doing this to get students to celebrate her sister's wedding.
Yes. And we're cheering her on.
I'll be cheering you on, too.
Good luck.
Thank you very much.
You take everything in stride, don't you?
It was nice to have her accept it, wasn't it, Fuu-chan?
Yes. It was thanks to you, Nagisa-san.
You're ignoring me?
Because you're Fuuko's enemy.
I'm not.
Then Fuuko's nemesis.
It's gotten worse!
It'd be better to say you're Fuuko's archnemesis.
Okazaki-san!
You can't pick on Fuu-chan.
So she enters that state when Nagisa hugs her, too.
Um, Fuu-chan?
Calling her name is useless.
She's gone for a while once she's in that state.
Fujibayashi!
Yes?
Can you come here for a second?
When she comes back to us, tell her,
”I'm Okazaki; I just turned into a girl.”
She's always spacing out,
so I want to give her a little warning.
Will you help me out?
Sure, I don't mind.
If she asks what happened, tell her, “It  falls off every now and then.”
For anything else, just say, “I guess.”
Yes.
We'll hide and watch.
Is this really for Fuu-chan's sake?
Um, what were we talking about?
Eh? Where did Okazaki-san and Nagisa-san go?
I'm Okazaki; I just turned into a girl.
I said, I'm Okazaki.
I just turned into a girl.
This doesn't make sense!
Why did you turn into a girl?
I-It  falls off every now and then.
That's too big of a shock!
So it… falls off every now and then?
Gosh…
I-I guess.
You guess?! It falls off that easily?!
Fuuko never knew such a person existed!
Looking at it in reverse, is there
a chance of one attaching to Fuuko, too?
I guess.
It could happen?! Fuuko is utterly shocked!
It reattached?!
What are you talking about?
So it was a bad dream, after all.
Thank goodness. Fuuko thought Fuuko might one day become Fuutaro.
Note: “Taro” is a typically masculine ending for a name
Okazaki-san, you should tell her soon.
There are two Okazaki-sans!
We split into two on occasion.
Fuuko is utterly shocked!
Hey, Tomoya!
I've been watching! Stop playing pranks using my sister!
Same face!
There are three Okazaki-sans!
How much longer can she do this?
“Switch the Person She's Talking To” Mastered!
Please.
You're giving these to us?
It's a big star.
Or maybe it's a starfish?
You're wonderful! You're part of Fuuko's starfish alliance!
What? This really is a starfish?
Yes. A sculpture of starfish Fuuko made with all her heart.
Umm… I meant it as a joke, but…
Give the starfish a hug.
Like this?
You look wonderful! It's great!
What kind of tastes does she have?
But they're both beautiful,
so seeing them lined up makes them look very nice.
Inside, they're completely different, though.
The older one is a gorilla and the younger is a hamster.
Okazaki-san!
You just said something really rude, didn't you?
You can't throw something you received.
Yeah! If you do that, Fuuko will be—
I-I'm sorry. It looked like it had
a good damage bonus, so I moved without thinking.
Flying starfish…
It's great!
Why?!
Everyone is accepting it.
Well, we are picking out kind people.
Mitsui-san!
It's Ibuki Fuuko.
We talked a little during the entrance ceremony, right?
Yes, I recall that.
You got into an accident, right?
Were you released from the hospital?
Um…
Yup.
She got released and is starting over as a freshman.
And we have a little favor to ask.
Please accept this!
What's this?
A present.
And if possible, Fuuko hopes you can come to Fuuko's sister's wedding.
I'm sorry, but I can't accept it.
You're a freshman, so you might not understand,
but seniors are at an important time with entrance exams.
I don't want to do anything that leads to a loss of time.
Excuse me now.
Fuu-chan…
Hey, why don't you cheer up already?
Fuuko is doing fine.
I'm saying so because you don't look like it.
Fuuko only got to talk to Mitsui-san
a little during the entrance ceremony.
It was good enough that she remembered Fuuko's name.
Fuuko hasn't attended any classes.
Fuuko is only picking up extra wood
and carving in open classrooms.
Fuuko wanted to attend classes, too.
All right then. Time to call Kyou and Sunohara then.
It looks lively even though it's the weekend.
Yeah, since the Founders Festival's coming up.
They must be getting ready for that.
Thanks to that, we can enter the campus, too.
Ah, there they are.
Good morning, Okazaki-san,
Furukawa-san, and Fuuko-chan.
Good morning, everyone.
Sorry to have you all come.
I came for Nagisa-chan, you know.
Thank you very much, Sunohara-san.
But Tomoya, why do we have to do this?
There are a few reasons behind it.
I'll explain all of them some other time.
What's wrong, Fuuko-chan?
Fuuko is a little nervous.
Come here, Fuu-chan.
Class will be starting soon.
Over here.
Get over here already.
We have the students,
but what are we doing about the teacher?
That's a problem.
I couldn't ask a real teacher.
Then is one of us doing the teacher role?
Not you, since you're an idiot.
You're so rude!
Okay.
Class is starting.
Sanae-san? Why are you here?
I heard the story from Nagisa.
If you're okay with it, allow me to fill the teacher's role.
Hey, Tomoya, who is she?
Nagisa's older sister?
Something like that.
Hot chick!
Looks like this'll be a fun class.
We have one person
in a different world from the rest of us.
Okay, everyone, please take your seats.
Sanae-san looks really comfortable with the teacher role.
Since this is the first class, I'd like everyone to introduce themselves.
Yes!
I'm Sunohara Youhei!
The kanji for Sunohara is spring-field.
My, that's a beautiful name.
Sensei, Sunohara-kun is an idiot.
Don't go saying things like that!
She would have found out soon enough.
Sunohara-kun, make up for it with your energy.
I'm Okazaki Tomoya.
I'm a lazy bum at school.
Yes, it's nice to handle things at your own pace.
I'm Furukawa Nagisa.
Sunohara-san and Okazaki-san are goofing off,
but I want to take the class seriously.
I guess that makes you the class rep.
N-No.
You should become the class rep.
No…
Rather than me…
I recommend Fuu-chan.
Since this class is centered around Fuu-chan.
I like that.
Fuuko! Are you up for it?
No objections.
Good luck with the position.
If that's what Nagisa-chan says.
So, class representative. Please introduce yourself.
Ibuki-
No, you're not!
Isogai Fuuko!
Fuuko likes starfish.
Good job.
Fuuko-chan.
Fuuko-chan, everyone you see
around you is your classmate…
…and is your friend.
Let's all get along well.
Yes!
Let's start the class now.
Class representative.
You have to say the words.
Yes.
Rise.
Bow.
Sit.
Ibuki Fuuko…
She's a little strange, but she's a normal girl
no matter how you look at her.
To be Continued
Preview
Ask Ibuki-sensei to come to the Founders Festival?
Yes. I'm thinking of inviting her to the festival and letting the two of them meet.
I see. That might be a good idea.
Um…
Um, pardon me.
Please have this.
I want to let Fuu-chan and Ibuki-sensei meet.
We promised to go to
the Founders Festival when she enrolls.
I'm happy for you, Fuu-chan.
Episode 6
The Sisters' Founders Festival
Yes!