Okazaki-san?
Okazaki-san!
Oh, what is it, Furukawa?
You've been acting strangely since this morning.
So he's gone back to being a weird person.
You're the only person that calls me weird!
I was talking about Ibuki-sensei.
She called me last night to say that the wedding will be next Sunday.
I see.
So Koumura must have received the principal's permission.
The day to witness the reward for your work is finally about to arrive.
Yes.
Please accept this!
Um, please accept this!
It feels like more and more people aren't taking them.
Not only do they not take them,
but it's as if they don't even notice Fuu-chan.
That's not all.
She's being forgotten.
We must be thinking too much.
You're not with Sunohara today.
He's skipping school right now.
It's been a while, Tomoyo-san.
Ah, you were…
I'm Furukawa Nagisa.
We met at the Founders Festival.
When Fuu-chan gave you the sculpture.
Sculpture?
This thing.
Tomoyo-san?
Yes, I remember!
Right, I received a sculpture from her.
It's very rude of me to forget about a present I had received.
But, this is strange.
Why did  I forget?
Okazaki-san?
Episode 8
A Wind that Disappears into the Twilight
We have a lot left today.
Don't worry. You have days like this, too.
He's right. We'll just work
harder tomorrow to make up for it.
There she goes again.
You came back fast today.
Fuuko's body just gave me a warning.
It said, “Run! He's dangerous!”
I bet it's your imagination.
It's not her imagination.
You were always playing pranks on Fuu-chan.
Like taking her to a different place,
or making her hug Sunohara-san's head.
So they were all your fault after all!
It's a petit horrible!
What's this “petit horrible” supposed to mean?
Fuuko is told that it hurts when you're called horrible, so it's a term Fuuko invented for Okazaki-san.
This way, you feel that it's cute
even if Fuuko uses it on you.
How was it?
It's meaningless unless you change the word “horrible”!
Fuuko can't change that!
If Fuuko has to change something, it'd be the “petit”!
Then change “petit” to “I am”!
I am horrible!
Wait, that makes Fuuko the horrible one!
So that doesn't work.
You two get along so well.
Hey, Mitsui!
Oh, you're from some time ago.
I'm sorry, who were you all?
Who are we?
You also got one from Fuuko, didn't you?
One of these.
This?
You accepted it, Mitsui-san.
And you said that you would celebrate Fuu-chan's sister's wedding.
I'm sorry. I'm afraid I don't remember.
Fuuko! We're talking about Fuuko!
Her! The person right in front of you!
Her?
No! There's another person!
I don't see anyone else.
Is this some kind of joke?
Excuse me.
Fuu-chan.
Fuuko!
Okazaki-san, what's going on?
She's starting to be forgotten.
It could be because her condition has worsened.
Everyone's starting to forget about her.
Maybe her existence itself is starting to disappear.
What?
Don't let it bother you, Fuuko.
Mitsui was just joking around with you.
If not, she was just misunderstanding us.
I-I think so, too.
Seniors are busy with entrance exams, after all.
Don't worry. You've got Furukawa and me with you.
I'm sure Sunohara will show up tomorrow.
And you even have your private guards.
Don't lose to something like this. Cheer up!
Yes. Fuuko will do her best.
Yeah, I'm getting better at this.
The starfish bread is very popular, too.
It seems we even have fans of it.
Seriously?
At the very least, Fuuko loves it!
That's great.
Then I'll make you some special starfish bread.
Really?
Fuuko's so happy!
Nagisa.  You're awfully quiet today.
Yes…
I was too absorbed in making the starfish.
Excuse me.
Hello.
You have a customer.
Don't talk to me. I'm working on a difficult part right now.
Someone for the shop is back there, right?
Hey, are you sure you don't need to go out?
It's fine. Just act like no one's here.
Akio-san!
If we're being this noisy, we can't pull that off.
Crap!
I think you should be making a different point.
You keep your loud mouth shut!
Oh no! First aid kit! First aid kit!
Sanae… I'm done for…
Please hold on, Akio-san!
U-Um, I'll go take care of the shop.
Yes… I leave the rest to you, my daughter.
Thank you very much.
It hurts!
Do it more gently!
I'm glad to see your family hasn't changed at all.
Akio-san! If you move around so much, I can't treat it!
Fuuko-chan, can you hold him down?
Okay.
Furukawa…
I know, I'm sorry.
I was holding it in, but…
What's going to happen now?
Will everyone start forgetting about Fuu-chan?
Maybe… both Okazaki-san and I will one day…
That's not going to happen.
We only have a little while left until the wedding,
so we need to be the ones supporting Fuuko.
That's right. Until the very end of her dream.
Hey!
What is it this time?
They're too picky regarding food,
so I was going to give them a little lecture.
They're acting like grade-schoolers.
Like I said, you're too kind.
Give a taste of your lethal moves to anyone who doesn't eat your food.
That'll be enough to change their attitude.
Does it go like that?
Oh yeah, Misae-san.
Here.
What is this?
Ibuki Kouko-san, a former teacher at our school, is getting married.
It's basically an invitation to the wedding.
What were you doing yesterday and today?
Fuuko was waiting for you, too.
Fuuko-chan, huh?
I skipped class and did some research on Ibuki Fuuko.
Why did you go and do that?
The person getting married this Sunday is Ibuki, right?
Then Fuuko-chan's last name has to be Ibuki, as well.
Isogai Fuuko is a fake name.
But Ibuki Fuuko is in the hospital.
Then who's the one that's always with us?
A fake Ibuki Fuuko?
If she is a fake, then that's fine.
But she isn't, right?
Then that makes Fuuko-chan a…
Okazaki.
Can I go confirm it?
Confirm what?
I'm thinking of going to the hospital to see Ibuki Fuuko's face.
You idiot! Don't!
Why?
If he sees Fuuko in the hospital,
I have a feeling he'll forget about Fuuko, too.
Okazaki.
You know something about Fuuko-chan, don't you?
If you don't want to say it, then I won't force you.
But I can't stop myself from needing confirmation.
Um, please accept this.
Um, please—
He used to be part of her private guards, too.
It looks like more people are
walking past her than yesterday.
Morning, Nagisa-chan!
You, too, Okazaki.
“Morning”? It's lunch break right now.
Did you just get here, Sunohara-san?
Well, something really weird happened, you know?
Maybe that's what it feels like to have amnesia.
When I came to, I was walking out of a hospital a city away.
I don't have a clue why I was even there.
I wonder why I went to a hospital.
Maybe I was sleep-walking?
Sunohara. Do you want Fuuko's starfish?
Fuuko?
You didn't receive one yet, did you?
Please accept this.
Hey, Youhei!
Kyou!
You came late again, didn't you!
Don't cry when you find yourself short in attendance!
Why are you worried about my attendance?
If you skip school, then it's your fault when my sister gets reprimanded by her teacher!
Fuu-chan.
What's that?
A sculpture of a star?
What are you guys doing with th—
Onee-chan, doesn't this seem familiar?
I was just having the same feeling.
She's Fuu-chan! We took classes together!
Look! She's right here!
Here! You guys should have these at your house, too!
Look for them! Remember her!
No, I can't remember anything.
God, this is annoying!
Onee-chan, calm down.
Fuu-chan.
It'll fade away from those who know her less.
One day, I'll also…
I don't want to forget.
If I forget about Fuu-chan, I won't be her friend anymore.
We played together at school
and ate meals together, and yet…
It's too sad to forget it all!
You were with Fuuko and cared about her more than anyone.
You won't forget about Fuuko, even if I do.
You think so?
Um, please accept this!
Where were you this weekend?
Please accept this!
I went on a trip.
Oh, where?
To Nikkou.
Um, please accept this!
Sorry, please accept this!
Hey there, you two.
Wanna go get lunch?
You go alone. We're busy.
Nagisa-chan. It's boring being alone with him, isn't it?
Let's go to the cafeteria together and talk about love.
U-Um…
Quit it!
What's his problem?
Hey, Fuuko-chan, you tell him, too.
What?
I just said something strange, didn't I?
You said a person's name.
You just said a girl's name!
Sunohara-san, please remember!
No, I can't.
I can't remember anymore.
But, I can feel it.
There was someone like that.
Um, this…
Why am I holding this?
What is this?
A star?
Maybe, a ninja star?
I don't get it.
Okazaki… Nagisa-chan…
Listen to me.
I didn't hate her.
At least, I don't think I did.
It's Fuu-chan, Sunohara-san.
She's Fuuko-chan!
Fuuko…
It's fine. That was enough.
Thank you, Sunohara.
He's a kind person.
He's an idiot!
When he saw Fuuko, he didn't bother trying to get along with her.
I'm sure he will come to Ibuki-sensei's wedding.
Are you going to attend the wedding in those clothes?
If Fuuko goes home, Fuuko has other clothes.
But you can't go home to get them, can you?
Since the ceremony is at school,
wouldn't the uniform be all right?
That's true, but…
How about we buy an accessory?
Fuuko doesn't have any money.
I'll pay for you if it's not something too expensive.
When's your birthday?
July.
It's a little early for a birthday present.
Then as commemoration for the day
she swore to never say “horrible” again.
Fuuko will continue to say it.
Then as a commemoration for graduating from starfish.
Fuuko will live with them for the rest of Fuuko's life.
We don't need a reason.
I think our feeling of wanting
to give her a present is enough.
You're right.
It doesn't suit her at all!
Okazaki-san!
He's very, very rude!
Hey, this looks like it's perfect for you.
It's a birthday party set.
Fuuko?
Fuu-chan?
Fuuko is sorry. Fuuko instinctively imagined wearing one on Fuuko's head.
Do you seriously want one?
Fuuko doesn't want it!
Then let's go.
You're such a child.
Fuuko can't get it out of Fuuko's head!
It's a very attractive item!
Fuuko is sure you two would be jumping on it if Fuuko wasn't here!
No, we wouldn't.
Fuuko is really, really happy.
If you're happy about it, then that's all that matters.
Fuuko is starting to get the feeling that you're not that bad of a person.
So you thought I was a bad person until this moment, huh?
Now, Fuuko likes you more than sea slugs.
Seriously! Yay!
I don't understand the ranking at all.
Fuuko likes sea slugs quite a bit, so you should be happy.
Aren't you glad, Okazaki-san?
Right now, in Fuuko's mind…
I don't want to be sandwiched between them.
Okazaki-san just has a bad mouth.
He's actually a person with a very warm heart.
Furukawa… I'm amazed how you can say such an embarrassing line.
Is it embarrassing?
I'll go on ahead.
Okazaki-san.
Okazaki-san! It's a fountain!
Fuu-chan! It's a fountain!
Hello.
We're home.
Is something wrong, Dad?
Ah, no, I just thought I saw a girl standing between you two.
I've been seeing things since this morning.
I feel like I'm forgetting something really important.
It feels like I might eat Sanae's bread by mistake.
At times like this, this is the best thing to do.
I guess I'll go play some ball with the kids.
Damn it!
Dad looked to be in a lot of pain.
He must not have completely forgotten yet.
Like Sunohara, Kyou, and Fujibayashi.
Fuuko knows.
The old man likes you, too.
That's why he's in so much pain.
Fuuko is happy if that's true.
Mom.
Um…
Welcome home, Nagisa, Okazaki-san.
And… Fuuko-chan.
Fuuko's home.
I'm home.
Did you all enjoy school today?
Do you want to take a bath with me today, too?
What do you think, Fuuko-chan?
With Nagisa, as well…
Mom…
I can't see Fuuko-chan!
I went to the hospital today.
Hearing that Ibuki-sensei is getting married,
I thought Fuuko-chan might be
Ibuki-sensei's little sister, so I went to check.
Sanae-san…
Since then, like Akio-san, Fuuko-chan has been slowly disappearing from my head.
She's still here, right?
Yes, she's here.
Right here.
Fuuko-chan…
You can stay in this house all you like.
Akio-san, me, Nagisa… We all consider you family.
So days like this really do come.
I'm sure both Dad and Mom have…
Do you want to head over to school, Fuuko?
There's Pops over at my place,
and I can't take you to Sunohara's place.
To be Continued
Preview
Okazaki-san.
Do you remember the dream that Fuuko had about you, Okazaki-san?
Dream?
The dream about the Starfish Festival.
The days after meeting you and Nagisa-san were very much like one.
You two would always take Fuuko to fun places.
Every day was like a festival, and it was very fun.
Thank you very much. Fuuko enjoyed it a lot.
Episode 9
Until the Very End of the Dream