Furukawa, aren't Sanae-san and the old man worried that you're not home right now?
I did tell them where I'd be.
That I'd be with Fuu-chan tonight.
What was the old man's reaction?
After he heard Fuu-chan's name, he tried to remember her.
I guess he hasn't forgotten everything.
Episode 9
Until the Very End of the Dream
If they find us here, we'll get yelled at, won't we?
If it happens, it happens.
Hey, you're being impatient.
Fuuko can't resist anymore!
You really are a kid.
Fuuko's just short!
Inside, Fuuko's more mature than you!
I don't want to hear that from a person
opening a toy package so enthusiastically.
Fuuko understands the point you're trying to make, but Fuuko's hands won't stop.
Okazaki-san?
It disappeared!
Fuuko's hat!
Over here.
Don't steal Fuuko's treasure!
If you're an adult, restrain yourself.
Fuuko will become a child for just this moment!
Fuu-chan!
Okazaki-san!
Give it back!
Okay, fine! I'll give it—
Are you two all right?
Ow…
Fuuko was a child only for that moment.
So forgive Fuuko.
Get off of me already!
You're heavy!
You're same age as me, right?
Act a little more mature.
You're much more of a child.
If you're an adult, you should be addressing girls who are close to you by their names.
Why are you taking the situation to such extremes?
Yuusuke-san calls Onee-chan by name.
And Onee-chan calls him Yuu-kun, as well.
They're both adults.
I call you by name, too, Fuuko.
What Fuuko is talking about is Nagisa-san.
Fuuko thinks you two are acting very distant, calling each other by your last names, when you're both very close.
If you're an adult, then you should be saying her name like one.
You're not making any sense.
H-He's right. Even if you say something like that all of a sudden…
Then try calling her by her first name.
I think Okazaki-san should address you with the “chan” ending,
and Nagisa-san should address you with the “kun” ending.
Ready, and go.
Nagi…
To… Tomoya-kun…
Na… Nagisa-chan…
I can't say it!
Me, too. This is a little too embarrassing for me to bear.
Then it's decided that you're both more childlike than Fuuko.
Wait. At least let me take the “chan” off.
That's what I do with Kyou and Tomoyo.
Then try it.
Nagisa.
Yeah, this is easier on me.
Yes, me too.
But, I need a little more time before I am able to call you by your first name.
Fuuko will accept that.
Why are you acting so bossy?!
Fuuko loves both Nagisa-san and Okazaki-san, so Fuuko wishes the best for you two.
Like Onee-chan and Yuusuke-san.
H-Hey…
There, it's done.
How does it look? How does it look?
You wear it better than anyone else in Japan could hope to.
No doubt about it.
You're really cute, Fuu-chan.
You're embarrassing me.
Fuuko's #1 in Japan!
What are you doing, being so excited now?
The wedding's the day after tomorrow.
Um, can't we have a pre-celebration now?
Pre-celebration?
Of the wedding?
The person getting married isn't here.
We can't do it without her?
I think it's fine.
Let's have one with just us.
Yeah.
There's a vending machine on the first floor.
And I'm sure the home economics room has a match, at least.
This is the best!
I bet you just want to party with that on your head.
That's absolutely not true!
Okay, everyone. Your words of tribute please.
Onee-chan, congratulations!
Kouko-san, congratulations!
Ibuki-sensei, congratulations!
Fuuko's ears are ringing.
Fuuko, you've got tape hanging off your head.
Um, you too, Okazaki-san.
Is this it?
Nagisa, you do, too.
Yes.
Are you cold at all, Fuuko?
Let's all get closer.
It'll be warm as if we're playing Oshikura Manju.
Note: Oshikura Manju is a children's game where kids huddle together and push each other.
It'll be like the Big Dango Family.
Doing this really makes us like a family.
You're right.
Fu-Furukawa…
What? Why was I asleep in a place like this?
Okazaki-san?
This is…
We stayed over at school last night?
It… looks like it.
Did we crash while we were thinking about how to reestablish the drama club?
It feels like that now that you mention it…
But it doesn't look like that here.
I'm sorry for sleeping out without letting you know!
Looks like we fell asleep without realizing it.
You think that kind of excuse is going to work?!
Akio-san!
Dad!
…Is what I'd like to say.
But I think I heard you tell me that you'd sleep out, my daughter.
Me, too.
I think I heard you say there was something important you needed to do, so you couldn't come home.
Um, do you remember what that “something” was?
Strangely, I don't remember.
This is annoying me.
Damn it!
Not to quote the old man,
but something's bugging me, too.
I feel like the thing I can't remember is something really important.
Okazaki-san, take a look at this.
There was something that looked exactly the same in the club room, wasn't there?
There was one in my room, too.
Though I don't remember where I got it from.
But looking at it calms me.
Do you get the same feeling?
What are you doing spacing out?
I'm trying to remember something.
“Something”? What?
I don't really know.
Oh, so you're bored.
Then hang out with me tomorrow. It's Sunday.
I'm going to go shopping with Ryou.
Tomorrow…
I think there was something scheduled for tomorrow.
What kind of vague way of rejecting me is that?
I'm not rejecting you.
I honestly feel there was something I needed to do tomorrow.
Something really important.
I see, so you do, too.
Yes. I feel there's something important to do tomorrow, as well.
Something has to be happening tomorrow.
Let's remember what it is.
Koumura-sensei.
What are you working on?
Can't you tell by looking at it?
Happy Wedding
Someone's getting married?
What a strange question.
Have you developed dementia at your age?
It's really depressing to hear that from you.
Take a good look at it and remember it for yourself.
Kouko-san!
Ibuki-sensei!
She's having her wedding here at school tomorrow because you two brought up the idea.
Yeah. That's right.
How could we have forgotten such an important thing?
Furukawa, why did I want to celebrate Kouko-san's marriage?
That's another strange question.
Because both of you know her well enough to celebrate her marriage, of course.
I think I'm the one who introduced Okazaki-san to Ibuki-sensei.
But I think there was one other person that brought us all together.
One other person…
Would that possibly be Ibuki-sensei's younger sister?
Younger sister?
I'll see you around.
Ibuki-sensei's younger sister…
Fuuko-chan!
That's right! Fuuko!
You…
Fuu-chan…
You've been standing by us all this time?
Yes.
I'm horrible, aren't I?
I tried so hard not to forget about you, and yet…
You're not horrible at all.
It was a natural occurence.
Don't say such a sad thing.
We always want to be with you.
Let's always stay together, Fuu-chan.
We'll stay together until the wedding happens.
Yes.
It's great how the weather held up.
Wedding Ceremony - Yoshino Family - Ibuki Family
I heard it was the bride's wish to hold the ceremony at the school.
Looks like there aren't any students here.
But Okazaki-san and Nagisa-san are here.
The rings hold two meanings.
First: Eternity.
Second: Completeness.
By exchanging rings, you both vow to be truthful to each other forever.
Now, repeat what I say.
This ring…
…I give to you as proof…
…of my eternal love for you.
Okazaki-san!
Where are you going?!
We're going to wait for them at the front gate!
We'll send them off with a voice louder than anyone else's.
Right, Fuuko?
Yes!
Okazaki-san…
What's going on?
Puhi! Puhi! Puhi!
Puhi! Puhi!
Kyou.
Fujibayashi.
I thought you two were going to go shopping.
Puhi! Puhi!
Yeah…
We were intending to…
Right?
When I saw this in the morning,
I remembered about the wedding.
It made me feel like I had to come celebrate it.
Yo.
Sunohara!
So you came.
Since I had some time to spare.
And look over there, too.
Dad. Mom.
We figured you'd be here, too, my daughter.
Indeed.
Something must have been wrong for us to have
forgotten the wedding until the day of the ceremony.
They reached them.
Your feelings!
They were well planted in everyone!
It's hard to believe.
I'm happy for you.
Yes.
Congratulations.
Okazaki-san.
Do you remember the dream that Fuuko had about you, Okazaki-san?
Dream?
The dream about the Starfish Festival.
When Fuuko was playing alone on the beach, you took Fuuko's hand.
Saying, “What are you doing alone? Today's the Starfish Festival.”
The days after meeting you and Nagisa-san were very much like one.
The two of you would always take Fuuko to fun places.
Every day was like a festival, and it was very fun.
Thank you very much. Fuuko enjoyed it a lot.
Okazaki-san.
Nagisa-chan.
Kouko-san.
Is something wrong?
You look sad.
Please listen to me, Kouko-san.
There was a person who longed to see this sight.
There was a person who worked hard for this day.
There's a person who gathered all of these blessings for you.
We love that person. We really love that person, so…
You two must have been with her this whole time.
We were with her because spending time with her was fun.
That's all.
The same applies to everyone gathered here.
So Kouko-san!
Please have a great life for her sake, too!
Yes.
Congratulations, Onee-chan.
Have a… Have a wonderful life!
Have a…
Have a wonderful life forever.
Fuu-chan?
Fuu-chan said congratulations to me.
Wished me a happy life forever.
I think she was giving me her blessing from her dream.
And that reached me.
As long as we hang on to the happy feelings…
…I'm sure she can be happy, too.
I can honestly believe that now.
Hey, did you hear the rumor about the girl who got in an accident two years ago and is unconscious?
I heard she's the younger sister of Ibuki-sensei, who got married the other day.
I heard she's very cute, too.
Who said she is?
It's only a rumor.
But, don't you get the feeling that she is?
How she's cute, earnest,
and always running through the school.
Yeah, I can see it.
Right?
Hey, it's been bothering me for a while, but what's that?
This? I found it in my room one day.
I don't have a clue where I got it from.
But this is “that”, right?
Yes.
Yup, “that”.
Starfish!
Why do we know that, though?
Hey you! Stop sleeping and join the conversation.
Tomoya!
Hey! Wake up!
Since who knows when, the school has been abuzz with rumors of the girl.
How she's innocent, earnest,
and always running through the school.
An image of such a girl.
And since who knows when, everyone's been waiting…
…for the day the girl wakes up.
I'm definitely one of them.
And eventually, that day will come.
If… you don't mind…
Please be Fuuko's friend!
Preview
Ryou-chan is a bully?
Yes. Since I think you're a fun person, too.
Will she bully me?
Yes, if that's okay with you.
Do I have to cry?
When the scene requires it,
then there are times you have to.
I don't want to cry.
Still when you have to, you have to.
Episode 10
The Genius Girl's Challenge
Nagisa-chan, are you a bully?
Yes.