Okazaki, it's morning.
Why are you here?
I'm here to wake you up, of course.
Where's Pops?
Oh, by the time I got here, he wasn't around.
Sorry for you having to make breakfast.
I'm the one who needs to apologize.
I should have been more careful.
Don't worry about it.
But you got suspended in place of me.
Honestly, I'm still thinking…
…that maybe I should run to
the faculty office and tell them the truth.
That's the one thing I don't want you to do.
I told you; I need you to become
the student council president no matter what.
For the sake of the drama club, right?
But—
Oh, what's this?
Good morning!
Please join us if you'd like.
Well, well. I haven't had a breakfast like this in a while.
I'll accept the offer.
Let me sit next to you, Tomoya-kun.
Thanks for the food.
It was good.
What's wrong, Okazaki?
Episode 18
Strategy for a Comeback
Bomb-a-head…
Sunohara, wake up!
God… What's this so early in the…
A girl's here to confess her love to you!
Seriously, yo!
Wow, what the hell are you doing?
What's strange?
The rugby club?
Are you a lingerie burglar?
Forget that, that's men's underwear!
What?
You freak!
Coincidences are scary.
Is it fun for you to do this?
It is.
Think of it as an alarm clock.
I've actually lost my mind several times because of it!
I'm going to head out to school soon. Are you planning to stay here all day?
Yeah. Give my regards to everyone.
He got suspended instead of Sakagami-san…
Really, he doesn't know how to keep himself out of trouble.
Will it be okay? Won't it affect his future?
I'm very worried.
The President is sick, and Tomoya is suspended.
Will we be able to take part
in the School Festival like this?
It's been three days, hasn't it?
Why do I keep thinking about her?
Hey! We're here to see you.
It seems you were caught in
a sticky situation, Okazaki-kun.
Oh, it's you guys.
What? Who did you think it was?
Oh, no one in particular.
Come to think of, if you're suspended, shouldn't you be at home?
But who's the one dragging me out?
Where are we going, Onee-chan?
Let's see…
They've set the atmosphere in here pretty well.
If it's a fortune-telling game, Ryou can enjoy it, too, right?
All right, put your name in now.
Y-Yes.
U-Um…
You use this.
Yes!
That's the symbol for a guy.
Friends - Lovers - Married
The couple's relationship?
Well…
Come on, do it!
O-Onee-chan!
But it says to put each other's hands on top of each other.
I'm sorry.
No, I'm fine with it.
Here goes.
Friends
Wha… What do you think you're doing?!
Hey…
Damn you! That hurt, Kyou!
It's because you made that choice that ruins the mood!
In a case like that, you're supposed to choose “lover” for the sake of situational entertainment!
A kind woman and a man with a strong sense of responsibility.
You two get along very well as friends.
Whether you can progress in your relationship depends on how each of you feels…
What a mundane answer.
Isn't all fortune-telling like that?
But I'm glad to see nothing like “horrible match” came out.
Onee-chan?
I've got something to do, so I've got to go now.
Tomoya, make sure you walk Ryou home.
Hey!
You really like stuff like that, don't you?
All girls like fortune-telling at the genetic level.
But in your case, you can't expect much accuracy.
I mean…
You're right. I never get it right.
Oh, so you knew.
Of course, it's a pity I can't get it right, but I think it's better that I don't.
Why?
If the results come true, it's as if there's only one future.
But if it fails, we can think that other futures exist.
We never know how the future shifts because of the slightest change.
I want to believe that in our future
there are many possibilities waiting.
You don't have to come on Sundays, too.
Let me do as I wish.
Where's Pops?
He just left.
Are things not going well with your father?
I'm sorry. It's not something I should be meddling in.
How's the presidential campaign coming?
Isn't the vote happening soon?
It's going well.
Don't worry about it.
Good morning. A little gift for you.
Puhi! Puhi!
Thanks…
I'm sorry. Onee-chan insisted on coming.
Yeah, um, ah…
What's wrong, Okazaki?
Do we have a guest?
You!
Tomoya-kun.
Kyou-chan, Ryou-chan.
Good morning.
What brings even Kotomi-chan here?
I made some food for you, Tomoya-kun.
I thought you'd be hungry alone.
The air in here is heavy.
Puhi.
I can't possibly eat all of this…
Ryou and I made this after waking up at five.
Of course, you will eat it, won't you?
I am the one responsible for getting
Okazaki suspended, thus making me involved.
I have an obligation to look after him.
What do you mean “involved”?
You make it sound like we're not.
Frankly speaking, you aren't.
I don't think you all are related to this matter at all.
Excuse me, we've known him since junior year and are part of the drama club, too.
Time and titles do not matter
with regards to the bonds between people.
Hey, you two. Don't get so worked up.
It's because you won't make up your mind!
Even if you say that…
Fujibayashi, help me out here a little.
I want…
…you to eat my cooking, too!
Puhi!
K-Kotomi…
Tomoya-kun.
Kotomi…
I worked hard on these,
and I've been preparing them since last night, too.
Fuuko's here!
Who are you?
Fuuko brought some food, too!
Okazaki-san, please leave this to Fuuko!
No, seriously stop it!
Fuuko fully understands how you all feel.
However, Okazaki-san should choose Fuuko's cooking.
Starfish baumkuchen!
Starfish cake!
Starfish cream puffs!
They look gross.
Okazaki-kun.
Please eat my bento.
My dishes, too.
Come on, eat up.
You know what choice you should be making.
Puhi puhi…
Pick the best choice, Okazaki-san.
Puhi.
Puhi?
Best…
Choice…
Bro!
Good work out there!
Don't be so loud…
I ate too much yesterday, so I have horrible heartburn.
Are you sure you have the time to lie around like that…
…when Tomoyo's in big trouble?
Is this true?
Gang Girl
I heard she was a big shot
gang member before coming here.
The other day, guys from another school came to get her.
Violent Tramp
But that's related to Okazaki, right?
Who knows?
Hey, he's right here!
You get it?
So what are you going to do?
What? A match?
Yeah. If we lose, we'll pick up balls or do whatever you want us to do.
Hold on just a moment. I'll go talk to the others.
Will this really increase support?
It's the same idea as when we played basketball.
I'm sure it'll work.
I've never done anything more than play catch.
Don't worry. We have
the super athlete, Sunohara, with us.
That makes me even more worried.
Okazaki!
You got yourself a deal.
But, under one condition.
If you guys lose, we'll have Sakagami join the women's softball team.
You've got it.
Tomoyo! Get three outs and we win!
If anyone gets on base safely, we lose!
I'll do my best.
All right, bring it on.
Hey, is she all right?
Hey now…
What is she doing?!
Shut up! You're distracting me!
If you dare end this with a walk,
I'll forever call you Heart of a Chicken!
We want a pitcher, not a belly itcher!
Calm down, Tomoyo.
Sunohara is pissing me off, so I can't concentrate.
In that case, aim for Sunohara's face.
Thinking of blasting him away.
His face…
We want a pitcher, not a belly itcher!
Okay, I'll do it.
Bring it on, Chicken Heart.
S-Strike.
Eh?
Strike, batter out!
This feels great.
We won, Tomoyo!
Did you hear about the junior, Sakagami Tomoyo?
She had a match against
the baseball team and won, right?
Wow, as expected from Tomoyo-senpai.
I'll go watch her.
Senpai!
You made all the bad rumors vanish.
Thank you.
It's fine. It's for the sake of the drama club.
Even so, I'm grateful to you.
At this rate, I think I can achieve my goal.
Your goal?
Right, I haven't told you about it yet.
I want to preserve the sakura trees here.
There's a plan to cut them all down.
The students that know about it don't like the idea.
People living around here are against it, as well.
If I become the student council president of this school,
I can act to preserve these sakura trees.
You transferred here just for that?
Yeah.
I wanted to preserve this place no matter what.
It's a very important place.
What were you like as a child?
Well, nothing special.
I had gone wild.
What do you think people become…
Or rather, what do you think keeps people from going wild?
Talents, perhaps?
If you have a talent, you can have
a clear image of what you want to do.
You can let yourself be absorbed in that.
That's a good answer.
Then, what if you can't find a talent?
Maybe relationships?
I see. That's a plausible answer, too.
The answer I found is “family”.
When there's family, it's easier to control oneself.
Not always!
There are cases where family causes one to have a wild life.
The “family” I'm talking about doesn't have to be a real family.
It can even be friends.
What it takes is a group that's like a family.
I don't mean to force the answer on others, but that's the answer I arrived at.
My parents didn't get along.
Inside my house it was totally cold, and there was no communication.
Not even any arguments.
Neither had done anything wrong.
But I'm sure small misunderstandings and hardships accumulated, and eventually, things no longer clicked.
I had gone wild for a long time.
I forced my anger and irritation on anyone and everyone.
I was a weak person.
The one who woke me up was…
…my younger brother, Takafumi.
A quiet, moderate, and kind guy.
But I wasn't a good sister at all.
I'd never seen him smile.
Two years ago, my parents were going to get divorced.
They fought over who'd take the children.
I didn't care how it ended.
But Takafumi didn't want that.
He didn't want to go with either one.
It was the first time he said anything like that.
And…
He jumped?
Yeah. He said he'd jump
if they were going to get divorced.
And he really did.
I don't understand at all why he did that.
It's not as though he wanted to die.
I don't think even he understood the rationale behind it.
But, with him doing that, we finally became a family.
He was ice cold, and we thought there was nothing we could do.
When spring came, he was finally discharged, and we walked down the road.
He said to me…
“I want to come and see these sakura every year with everyone, as a family.”
I felt the same way… and so did my parents.
The city will change.
But there are many people who treasure these sakura trees.
Not just me.
Many people who live in this city feel that way.
No matter how depressing a place may look, the most important places don't change.
I think there's a similar aspect to family, as well.
Nagisa! Welcome back!
It really has been a while.
I'm glad to see you're better.
I'm sorry I worried all of you.
Okazaki-san.
Wh-What?
I'm sorry.
I heard you got yourself suspended to make Sakagami-san the student council president.
I have no clue how I should even begin to apologize to you.
It's all right.
It wasn't solely for your sake.
I did it for the drama club.
If you phrase it like that, it sounds condescending.
Ah, well…
Anyway, it's in the past.
If you want to take responsibility,
then help Tomoyo with her matches after school.
Y-Yes.
It'll be a one-set match.
If I win, I'll have you join the tennis team.
Agreed. Let's have a good match.
I wish she was playing a girl.
Will Sakagami-san be all right?
There's a huge audience.
Okazaki-kun.
Yeah, good!
All right!
Onee-chan.
The match's already started.
You're keeping a good pace for now.
Yeah.
Sakagami-san, would you like a drink?
Are they changing courts next?
They are?
I don't need it now. Thank you though.
We've met before, too, haven't we?
You're…
I'm Furukawa Nagisa.
I'm trying to reestablish the drama club.
The drama club…
I see, so that's how it is.
No, it's nothing.
I'm going out again.
Nagisa!
Nagisa-chan!
What happened?
I'm sorry, are you all right?
Nagisa-chan?
Are you all right, Nagisa?
I'm all right.
That was Sakagami-san's point, right?
We need to treat it.
You should go to the health center.
Okazaki-san?
Let's go to the health center.
Y-Yes.
We'll walk slowly.
Yes.
Well, I knew it all along.
Onee-chan.
Onee-chan…
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry about all this.
Come on, what are you…
I'm sorry… I'm sorry…
To be Continued
Student Council President - Sakagami Tomoyo
Preview
Congratulations on getting
the drama club reestablished.
I made lots of food to celebrate the occasion.
If it hadn't been for everyone here,
I don't think I could have done a thing.
It's just been your father around since you were little, right?
Despite living in the same house, we carry on with our lives separately.
Pops and I haven't been family for a long time.
Episode 19
New Life