Those who agree, please raise your hand.
With the voice of the majority, both the choir club and
the drama club will have Koumura-sensei as their advisor,
and they are hereby officially
granted permission to be active.
You finally did it, Nagisa.
Yes.
Congratulations on getting
the drama club reestablished.
I made lots of food to celebrate the occasion.
Thank you very much. This is all thanks to your support.
I did a lot, didn't I?
Did you do something?
I was the one playing the basketball match
as well as the one helping with Tomoyo's election!
If it wasn't for everyone here,
I don't think I could have done anything.
There are no words to express my gratitude.
We can't relax now, though.
The School Festival is coming up
before the summer break.
Our goal is to take part in it.
Will we still make it in time?
What are you hesitating about now?
Okazaki-san…
Wasn't this your dream?
Now that it's right in front of you,
there's no time to hesitate.
You have to get excited
and reach out for it no matter what!
Yeah.
You're right.
I will work for it excitedly.
Visit my house?
I'll go meet your father today.
I want to discuss your future with him.
You don't have to.
Of course I have to.
You were suspended the other day, too.
Your father's at home, right?
Yes and no.
He might be out today.
Anyway, I'll go and see.
I'll get my stuff together, so wait here.
Okazaki-san.
What's the matter?
What are you  doing here?
I wanted to get advice from Koumura-sensei.
I need to start practicing a lot starting today!
Will you come with me?
I don't care about that.
I'm going home.
Okazaki-san!
You're contradicting what you said earlier.
You told me to excitedly reach out for it.
My hesitation disappeared with those words, and yet you're…
We'll talk about that later.
Okazaki-san!
Why are you chasing me?
Well, where are you going?
Okazaki Tomoya from 3-D. Okazaki Tomoya.
Come to the faculty office immediately.
You don't have to drag me. I won't run away.
I won't let go.
You can't trust my words?
Right.
Without a moment of thought.
Since occasionally you're a liar…
Episode 19
New Life
This is an amusing scene.
Okazaki being tamed by a girl.
It isn't like that.
Usually, he's the one who takes care of me.
Okazaki has changed a little.
Can you come with us?
Make sure Okazaki won't run away.
Yes. If I can be of help.
D-Don't you have business with Koumura?
Ah right. That's important, too.
Geez. Stop slacking.
How do you tolerate his harsh language?
I've become used to it.
It's just been your father around since you were little, right?
Yeah.
It must have been hard for him.
Think about raising a guy like you alone.
Wouldn't know.
Looks like he's out.
All right then. I guess I'll wait inside.
Huh?
That's how my job is.
I'll wait until tomorrow morning if I must.
I'll… go look for Pops.
Hey, Okazaki!
Should I head over to Sunohara's place?
Okazaki-san.
You ran away, didn't you?
What happened to your practice?
Koumura-sensei wasn't there, so we broke for the day.
I thought I would bring your bag.
Make sure you follow me, Okazaki-san.
What is Tomoya-kun saying?
No, I came today because I wanted to talk with you.
I will talk with him personally, too, but today I wanted to hear what you were thinking.
Like I said, that's not something for me to decide.
Tomoya-kun is Tomoya-kun.
It's something for him to decide himself.
But he's still a student, so I must hear his guardian's opinion.
No, Tomoya-kun is Tomoya-kun.
It's not something I should meddle in.
He's like that.
In his mind, I'm no longer his son.
I told you before how I got in a fight with Pops, hurt my shoulder, and couldn't play basketball anymore, right?
He's been like that ever since.
Despite living in the same house, we carry on with our lives separately.
He has a gentle smile like that and has always lived alone.
Pops and I haven't been family for a long time.
Um, Okazaki-san.
Would you like to come over to my place?
Only if… it isn't imposing on you.
No, not at all.
I think it'd be good if you maintained a little distance from each other and thought things over.
You two are a family,
so once you're apart, I'm sure that
each of you will grow to miss the other.
Then you'll remember how you loved each other,
so that the next time you meet,
you'll be able to sit and talk.
But, your father would…
Don't worry about him.
He's lived alone just like that.
I see.
But you should visit your home once in a while.
Yeah. Once in a while.
The house I always returned home to…
…but no longer.
A place I may never return to.
Or, maybe a day will come when I'll be able to return?
Who knew you could have a dish with such freshness so deep in the mountains?
And what's best is the personality of the owner here.
I'm sure you'll be happy enough that you came here simply to see her.
But that's not all.
I plan to go with my family over summer—
Tomoya-kun. Are you going somewhere?
To my friend's house.
You have a big bag there.
I'll stay there for a while.
I haven't decided when I'm coming back.
I see. It'll be lonely here.
Since you were good company.
I have issues, too.
Bear with me.
You're right.
I'm off now.
Goodbye, Father.
Hello.
What business do you have here this late?
Has Nagisa not told them about me yet?
If you don't have any, then go home.
You're in our way.
Um, where's Nagisa?
Welcome, Okazaki-san.
I look forward to spending the coming days with you.
Same here. Thank you for your hospitality.
Hospitality? What are you talking about?
Okazaki-san will be staying at our place for a while.
What was that?
You heard it from Nagisa a moment ago, right?
Yeah, I did.
You knew…
Yeah.
But Sanae…
Yes?
It's really sad for a guy to lose his harem, you know?
Okazaki-san, you don't have to worry about Akio-san, so please come in.
Yes.
You should at least look a little guilty, you know?
Yes, yes. Let's get back to work, shall we?
I've been waiting for you, Okazaki-san.
I can use a room this nice?
It's usually a guest room.
The futon is in here.
If you're not used to it,
I can take it out and put it back for you.
That's fine. I can do it myself.
You can't leave it out all the time, okay?
You're actually a pragmatist, huh?
That's not true.
I have my hands full with my own stuff.
But you're always worried about others.
Am I?
Seconds, Sanae.
Okay.
I'm out.
Hey. Good bath, right?
Would you like some tea?
Yes, thank you.
It's almost uncomfortable.
I guess I'll get used to it soon enough.
Well then, we'll be going.
Yes. Take care.
Okazaki-san, you have to say it, too.
Me too?
Yes!
Uh…
We're off.
Have a good day.
We're off, Dad.
Yeah. Take care.
Okazaki-san.
Y-Yeah.
I-I'm off.
Yeah. Go and score!
Score with what?
It was a little embarrassing, but both Sanae-san and the old man sent us out really naturally.
It's really fun to walk to school together.
It's a little embarrassing for me.
It is a little for me, too.
But thanks to you, I've gained a lot of confidence in many things.
I'll give it my best from today until the day of the School Festival.
Yeah, that's the spirit.
Yes.
Costume prepares the costumes and props.
Sound plays music and sound effects.
Lighting lights the stage.
It's very, very complicated.
Looks like we need to distribute the roles.
You can do Sound, can't you?
Since you played along with Kotomi.
Looks like a lot of trouble.
Why are you here?
I was curious what happened to the drama club after the election.
It's part of my job as Student Council President.
The workloads of Lighting and Sound depend on the play.
A play with a fast tempo will involve a more complicated use of the equipment.
The sound effects can be played with that keyboard.
This?
Hair-raising.
Hey, that's a great sound!
Hey, this isn't a game.
Oh come on. Let me play with it a little.
What was that, Nagisa-chan?
Eh? What?
Instead of Okazaki,
you like me more?!
I see. I understand.
We shall live alone in a forest nobody ever enters.
The two of us, holding hands, will run through the forest wet from the dew.
However!
We turn around, and there's a furious Okazaki!
And ahead of us were…
The murderous combination of Kyou and Tomoyo with fangs sharpened.
They didn't have to punch me.
But that skit was fun.
Nagisa.
Yes?
You said you had a play you wanted to perform, right?
How does it go?
Well…
I'm not sure myself.
To summarize: You know the play you want to perform, but you don't know the title.
Yes.
We're home.
We're back.
Who are these kids?
They are students of the Furukawa Cram School.
Furukawa Cram School?
What? That's not our teacher.
Hey, that's my stuff!
Nat-chan is in danger!
Okazaki-san!
Okay, everyone. Let's start.
Okay.
I'm sorry. I couldn't get a separate room ready in time.
You were the teacher of a cram school?
Yes.
Sensei. Please forget about that guy and start class.
What do you mean, “that guy”?!
Okazaki-san.
Everyone. You shouldn't speak like that to people older than you.
Okay.
Hey, if you're not busy with anything, help with the shop.
In fact, you should stand here and free me up.
We're most busy during mornings and evenings.
The bread I bake is pretty popular, you know.
Is Sanae-san all right?
Some kind-hearted people buy her bread once in a while.
I'm not talking about the bread. I mean the cram school.
Isn't it hard to deal with kids?
You don't have to worry about that.
That's Sanae's real job.
She was once a teacher at a middle school.
Seriously?
Why did she quit being one?
A lot happened.
I'm tired.
May I come in?
Feel free.
You need something?
Not particularly.
It just felt strange that you're staying at my house, so I couldn't help but visit.
It's not rare to have visitors at your place, right?
You let Mei-chan stay, too.
Yes, but you're a special case.
Um, if I'm bothering you, I can leave.
You're not a bother at all.
It's just… how do I say…
It's strange to me, too.
Strange, you say?
Yeah. By the time I was aware of things around me, my mother was already gone.
Pops is… you know.
Seeing a family that gets along well gives me a strange feeling.
You're right. Dad and Mom take really good care of me.
Yet, I have something I haven't apologized to them for that I should have.
Did you do something bad?
I can't say for sure,
but when I was little, it felt like
I did something really bad to Dad and Mom.
Maybe you're just imagining things.
Both Dad and Mom say that.
They always change the subject whenever I ask them.
But I can tell they are hiding something.
Since Dad always softens at times like that.
I'm sure there's something hidden that I have to apologize for.
Something you have to apologize for…
I want to find out what it is.
I want to know about it and apologize.
That's how I've always felt.
I'm sorry. I started talking when you didn't even ask about this.
It's fine with me.
Nothing strange about it.
Right.
Okazaki-san! The bath is ready!
I'm sorry; I'll get in later.
You go first.
I'm heading out to Sunohara's place a bit.
I've got to visit him once in a while,
or else he'll be lonely.
I see.
Please don't come back too late.
Man, this room is so relaxing.
Tea.
I told you, we don't serve that here.
You didn't bring a bento or something with you today?
Yeah, since I already had dinner.
Let me guess. At Nagisa-chan's place, right?
How'd you know?
I'm so envious of you.
So you say, but it's kind of uncomfortable to stay there.
It's great that they're letting me stay,
but I can't get used to the homey atmosphere.
Hold it right there!
You're staying with Nagisa-chan?!
Damnit.
I can't take this.
Don't get it wrong. I'm only having them let me stay for a while.
She's doing a favor for me since she found out that Pops and I don't get along.
What more do I need to know than that you guys are staying together?
So basically her parents approve of you.
Like I said, we're not like that!
Unbelievable… You're still saying that?
What does it matter…
I feel sorry for Nagisa-chan.
I'm collecting junk in an effort to make another doll.
Do you want a friend?
Of course. It's lonely to be by yourself..
I'm sorry.
She's not entirely correct.
I only thought, if there were more beings like me,
this place would become more lively.
Let's give it a try.
Even if it might not work.
To be Continued
Preview
No, I don't recall anything like that.
Ask Sanae about it.
I see…
All right then.
Hey, brat.
I don't know what you're trying to find out.
But, even if you do, don't tell Nagisa about it.
Why?
‘Cause I said so.
Got it?
I probably shouldn't go.
Episode 20
Secret Past