Hitotsu hegi hegi ni hegigoshi hachikami.
Bongame, bongome, bongomou.
Tsumitate tsumi mame tsumi sanshou.
Choshadan no chashoujyou.
Okome no namagami. Ohome no namakami.
Konkogome no namakakami.
Shusu. Hisuzu. Shusu. Shuchin.
Oya mo kahei. Ko mo kahei.
Oyakahei, kokahei. Kokahei, oyakahei.
Furu kuri no furu kirikuchi.
Amagappa. Kabangappaka.
Kisama no kyahan mo kawagihan.
Shikka bakama no shippo korobi wo.
Minna de tabinaga ni chotto muite.
This is so difficult.
Mudo soto sono nakade kawara sekiniko sekichiku.
I'm feel like I'm going to bite my tongue.
Nora nyorai. Nora nyorai. Mina nyorai. Munora nyorai.
Choto saki no okoho botoke ni okesu na okyaku ga
Hosonaga ni, hosodomo ni, hosonoyo ni.
Kyou mo nama nama nara nara nama no mama.
What are these long ass sentences about?
Choto shiokande, ochato chatacho chatto chotato chotecho.
Old man Koumura gave them to us.
They're supposed to help us
practice vocalization and articulation.
Aoda tokasen de hochacha tochaha.
Hey! Stop chatting and join back in!
Koo ha koo de moo ni koo.
Kouya no yama no okera kozou.
Fine, fine.
Tanuki hyappiki, ashi hyakuzen.
Tenmoku hyappai, bou happyappon.
Bugubagu bugubagu, nibugubagu.
Awasete bugubagu, mugububagu.
Kikukuri kikukuri, miki kukuri.
Awasete kikukuri muki kukuri.
Mugi gomi mugi gomi nimugi gomi.
Awasete mugigomi mumugi gomi.
Ano nageshino no nage naginata ha dada nagenawa no fuhou no.
Nagisa, are you making progress with the script?
Yes. I'm writing a little at a time as I remember the story.
I think I can finish it by tomorrow.
Ryou and Kotomi will do Sound.
Youhei and I will do Lighting.
Tomoya can do Effects and Directing, right?
Yes, and I'll be the actor.
It's starting to look more and more like a drama club.
There are still so many things we need to decide.
Like the costume and music.
What should we do about the costume?
Anyone good with sewing?
I guess I could give it a shot, but…
I'm not confident in mine, either.
Then that leaves…
Episode 21
In Preparation for the School Festival
Leave it to me.
See? It was a good call to ask her.
But Mom's busy.
Don't worry. I'll work on it a little here and there as I find the time between work.
I feel bad for her.
There isn't anyone else who can possibly do it.
Yes, but still…
So you're back, my daughter
who carries my superb genes…
…plus one.
Who are you calling “plus one”?!
We're home.
Yeah. Hey, I rented a good thing for you.
Here.
Hey, where is this place?!
There's nothing to worry about.
Look at this gorgeous view!
How splendid!
It's a world fitting for you.
A video of a play, huh?
Yeah, it looks like it'll be a good reference.
Yes, I've never seen a theatrical play, so this really helps.
You've never seen a play?!
No, I didn't even get the chance to watch
an elementary school play since I was sick.
Yet another bomb dropped by the President.
Hey, you can't research while crying.
But, I'm really touched.
I never knew drama was this amazing.
Compared to this, mine's like child's play.
So what if it's child's play?
If you put your heart into it, people will understand.
Yes. I think you're right.
What's this? You were flirting with Nagisa this late?
We were watching the video you got her.
Perfect timing. Come with me for a bit.
You were looking for something, right?
Operation Potty-Chair starts now.
I told you we're not looking for a potty-chair.
Can't seem to find it.
Are you sure this picture or children's book
you were looking for is hidden in the house?
It might be a theatrical play after all.
It's possible that Nagisa saw
a play in the past and forgot about it.
That's impossible.
If she'd seen something
like that, I'd definitely know.
Since I don't recall anything like that, there's no way.
Is it…
Hey.
You found it?!
No, this isn't it.
It's the potty-chair Nagisa used to use!
Why are you so hung up on the potty-chair?
You moron! I didn't find it because I was looking for it!
Both of you, please keep it down.
Look, she yelled at us.
You're saying it's my fault?
I got a great idea from watching the video!
What is it?
A song! If we insert a song at the climax, I'm sure it'll be very exciting!
You can sing well?
I've only sung in music classes.
But I think it'll become really good if we insert a song.
You don't think so?
I'm not denying it.
But, maybe you shouldn't worry too much about making the play a masterpiece.
You think so?
It's not a big production play, so do as you like.
Since it's a stage you made for yourself.
A stage I made…
You're right, and I want to sing.
So I'll sing.
I think that's what counts the most.
Yes.
This is a world that has ended.
A world where no one exists aside from myself.
In the room is a small table and a chair.
Beyond the window is a barren and expansive plain.
Is this interesting?
Yes, I think it's interesting.
We conducted some research,
but couldn't discover the title.
The story isn't complete yet, right?
Yes.
So, do you know any music that'll fit well as BGM?
What do you think, Rie-chan?
I have a picture in my head.
All you have to do is put yourself in the girl's shoes.
Put yourself in the girl's shoes…
It's not about being alone at school or home,
but being alone in the world.
It's a very sad thing, isn't it?
Yes, it's a very sad thing.
Music with a sad tone will probably fit well.
Wow!
Are all of these CDs yours, Nishina-san?
Rie-chan loves music, after all.
How about this one?
It's a song called Ma Mère L'Oye by Ravel.
Ma Mère what?
Ma Mère L'Oye.
It's Mother Goose.
Since your play has a fantasia-like mood,
I thought it would fit well.
Ravel composed many fantasia-like pieces.
This piece was for a Märchen.
It's wonderful! It's surprising how perfectly it fits!
I'm glad you like it.
It's really lively in here.
Sakagami-san. Hello.
Why are you wearing glasses?
Because my eyes are bad, obviously.
But you never wore them before.
I don't like how glasses look on me very much.
Then how about getting contact lenses?
Those are scary.
I understand that feeling well.
Forget about me!
How are things going here?
As you can see, we're making good progress.
But we still have lots to do.
We're only getting started.
The path we are taking is still continuing.
Let us both keep working hard.
It's a promise.
Yes.
As I thought, you're a good girl.
I'm glad it was you.
She's one hell of an underclassman, isn't she?
I'll try acting along with the music now.
Will you watch?
A room that was once empty.
But now, there are many people gathered here.
We all share this time together as Nagisa works hard…
…so we can share the joy together, too.
You really are amazing, Nagisa.
We'll be going now.
We're off.
Tomorrow's finally the School Festival.
Get the rehearsal down good.
Yes! I'll get it down!
Relax a little.
Today's just practice.
The real thing is tomorrow.
You've practiced so much that once you're on the stage, your body will move on its own.
You're right.
You're really cute, you know.
I'm sorry, can you wait until later?
Woah there.
She's really approaching the limit.
This row is starting to get crooked!
Bring some sheets over here, too.
This looks very complicated.
I agree.
My hands are getting tired.
Nagisa, don't move, all right?
Otherwise we won't know the position.
A little higher!
Yeah, we need the light in the center!
Okay, try turning it on!
I'm getting really nervous.
I don't think so. This was something my kid asked me for.
I can't give it to you so easily.
It's not something you can find lying around just anywhere.
It gets pretty dark on the side, huh?
Yeah, we'll need a flashlight tomorrow.
My heart's pounding really hard.
Relax, relax. Imagine that the seats are
filled with something other than people.
What should I think they are, then?
If not people, then how about aliens?
Isn't something wrong with that?
They've come to invade the Earth, so they won't care what you do.
I don't want them to be completely oblivious!
I want them to watch!
In that case, your acting determines if the Earth will be invaded or not.
If you put on a good performance for the aliens, then there'll be no invasion.
But if you give a poor performance, the world gets wiped away.
That puts huge pressure on me!
Hey, she's really reaching her limit,
so quit the idiot talk.
But I'm starting to calm down.
Seriously?
The drama club is up next.
Are you ready?
Y-Yes. We're good.
Okay, give it your best.
I'm starting to get nervous again.
You just said you were calming down.
I'm sorry, but when I think about
how hard you've all worked for me…
It's not just for you.
Or rather, we're all here to make this moment an enjoyable one.
I… guess…
The School Festival is run by everyone participating in it, so don't take all the pressure on yourself.
Yes. I think you're right.
Drama club. If you're ready, please begin.
Okay!
Let's give this a go!
It's just something I saw on the TV before,
but we should huddle up, put our hands together, and do a “Let's go!” kind of thing.
I saw one of those, too. That's so cool.
I want to try it, too.
All right everyone, hands in.
I did this all the time when I was on the soccer team.
Drama club, let's go!
Yeah!
Off you go, Nagisa.
Yes!
Let's all take positions, too.
Yup.
Let's go, Youhei.
Crap, I'm starting to get nervous, too.
Thank you, everyone.
We're home.
We're back.
Welcome home.
Welcome back, the fruit of our love.
By the way, you're not included.
I know that.
How did the rehearsal go, Nagisa?
Well… How did it go?
Flawless as usual, like all the other practices.
I'm glad to hear that.
As expected of our daughter.
By tomorrow, all of the idol agencies will be looking for you.
You're exaggerating things now.
Just agree with me, damn you.
Okazaki-san never flatters.
Yeah, I know. That's why you can count on him, right?
Nagisa, can I have your autograph while I have the chance?
What doting parents.
The same thing will happen to you once you have a daughter, too.
I swear it won't.
I can see you having one,
since you are very much like Dad.
What? Me and him?!
My daughter…
Yes?
Daddy's really shocked.
Don't say that when I'm right here.
Come in.
Will you be going to bed soon, Okazaki-san?
No, not yet.
Then, may I come in?
Sure.
May I sit next to you?
Is something wrong?
No, it's nothing in particular, but…
You're so nervous you can't sleep?
Can you tell?
I'd be more surprised to find that you were sound asleep.
You're right. I'm a nervous wreck.
It's your first stage performance, so it's to be expected.
Take the opportunity to get as nervous as you can.
Okay. I will do my very best to get nervous.
The old man and Sanae-san
will be at the performance, right?
Yes…
What's the matter?
It's just that I realized how much
I'm loved by Dad and Mom again.
I'm sure. It's hard to find parents like them.
I still can't stop thinking about
what happened when I was a child.
The thing where you feel like you've done something bad to your parents?
Yes.
Because of what Nagisa would probably think.
That because of her, Sanae and I
had to give up on our dreams.
Okazaki-san, is something wrong?
Nothing.
You know, Nagisa.
Yes?
You're being overly sensitive about all that stuff.
You have a habit of thinking you're at fault,
so this is just your imagination, as well.
You need to concentrate on
tomorrow's performance right now.
Think about other stuff after that.
You're right…
Okay, I'll do that.
Good night, Okazaki-san.
Yeah, good night.
Okazaki-san.
Um…
Thank you very much for listening to me.
Make sure you don't forget anything for tomorrow.
Yes.
Costume…
Towel…
Oh, right. Flashlight.
Nagisa?
Okazaki-san…
These pictures…
I found some old albums and diaries.
Okazaki-san, I never knew about this.
I never knew Dad used to act.
It seems like… they both gave up on their dreams for me…
Nagisa, don't think about any of that!
You need to give your body a rest.
I'll clean this place up.
You need to get some sleep, even if it's only a little.
Do you hear me?
After picking Nagisa up at kindergarten, we took a stroll to the river bank.
I'm really happy to be able to be with Nagisa every day.
If I had continued to work as a teacher, I don't think I would have been able to experience this joy.
Old man.
What a mess…
This is the worst time for her to find out.
Damn it.
To be Continued
Preview
The two people in the pictures looked like they were enjoying their lives.
Of course they were,
since they were living out their dreams.
And it was supposed to last forever.
You've wrong!
Besides, they're enjoying their lives right now, too!
But they gave up on their dreams.
Am I wrong?
And right now, I'm trying to live out
my own dream after sacrificing theirs.
Final Episode
Two Shadows