It's the same as Nagisa-san.
Unfortunately, I cannot tell the cause.
But I would guess that the same suffering Nagisa-san went through will come.
Just a second ago...
...she was running around.
I'll be going now.
Tomoya.
Who's her father?
Me.
Then you have to keep your head.
Are you all right?
Are you cold at all?
As a doll, I don't feel cold.
But I'm sure her hand is cold.
Although I can't even tell that.
The world will soon turn completely white.
We need to hurry a little.
Episode 21
End of the World
The sports day.
Yeah.
You're not going to run, Daddy?
I'll be with you the whole day.
Akki?
He might run. If two anchors skipped,
they'd have trouble finding two replacements.
Daddy. Beat Akki.
I said I'll be with you.
I don't like this.
So you're on my side, huh?
Yup.
I'm on your side, too.
No matter what happens, I'll protect you.
Yup.
Are you sleepy?
Don't worry. I won't go anywhere.
Okay.
One week...
Two weeks...
Then a month went by,
and Ushio's fever did not go down.
She couldn't go to kindergarten, much less leave the room.
I'm sorry.
I don't want you leaving us.
But, looks like there are a variety of issues.
That was a big decision.
Sanae-san and the old man tried to stop me,
but I want to be with Ushio.
Do you have anything saved up?
Some.
I was saving up for her education.
I see.
Good work here.
Thank you for your guidance.
Take it. Don't lose it.
Are you sure?
Of course not. How will I work without it from tomorrow on?
Then-
Lend me yours instead.
I'll give it back to you when you return.
Come back when Ushio-chan recovers.
I'll borrow yours until then.
I'll take good care of it.
Ushio stayed home.
We thought about putting her in a hospital but decided not to.
Since we don't know the treatment for it,
there was no point in staying at a hospital.
Most of all, Ushio wanted to stay home.
Let's change into new pajamas.
Okay.
You don't have to get up. I'll change you.
I can do it myself.
It's all right if you can't do it yourself right now.
Okay...
Ushio can't get changed alone anymore.
She can't go to the bathroom alone.
She can only eat soft foods.
Won't those peaceful days ever come back again?
Ushio, do you have anything you want?
If you do, tell me.
I'll buy you anything; toys or snacks.
I want to go on a trip.
Trip?
I want to go on a trip with Daddy again.
That wasn't fun at all, was it?
I was in such a bad mood and yelled the entire time.
It was fun.
I want to go on another trip.
On a train with Daddy.
Once you get better, okay?
I want to go now.
Ushio... Don't ask for the impossible and trouble me.
I can't even grant the one wish my only daughter has?
Nagisa...
What should I do?
If only you were here at times like this.
I'm...
My family might just be getting toyed with by this city.
Given happiness, then having it snatched away.
Unforgivable.
I will save Ushio no matter what it takes.
I will save Ushio!
Please look after her.
Have a good trip.
See ya.
Hey.
Take it.
I can't.
Don't be so stubborn.
No, I don't mean it like that.
I still have some savings,
so we'll be okay for a while longer.
I'll beat you up if you're lying to me.
I'm telling the truth.
Then fine.
There are things a man has to protect even if it kills his pride.
Right?
I know.
If I run into something serious, I'll let you know.
Want one?
No, I quit.
That's wise of you.
Hey.
People built this hospital by sacrificing the forest that was here.
What will the next sacrifice be?
A hill on the outskirts of town is getting dug up.
Apparently, they're building a shopping mall there.
It'll be convenient, so it's great for people.
Maybe...
From the moment you brought the near-death Nagisa here, Nagisa was linked to this city.
And Nagisa's daughter, Ushio, too.
Does... Is going through change a pain for the city?
I think it's got nothing to do with pain.
"Oh, I'm changing."
I think that's all.
If people's deaths are a part of changing, then do we have to accept that, too?
People build hospitals because they don't want to do that.
Let this city and its people be blessed.
Are you thirsty?
Do you want some water?
It's cold, so drink slowly.
If you go too fast, you'll get a stomachache.
It's good.
Really?
Daddy.
I want to go on a trip.
Sure. After you get better.
Where do you want to go?
Do you want to go to that flower patch again?
Ah, but going north now would be cold.
Let's go south.
To a place where it's warm, beautiful, and there's clean air.
Or-
I want to go now.
After you get better.
I've told you so many times, haven't I?
Now.
I want to go now.
To the flower patch.
Ushio...
It has to be now.
I want to go with you.
Okay, let's go.
I'll let you have your wish.
Yup.
But you have to let me know when you're not feeling well.
Good.
I'll give you a piggy back ride. Here.
I'll walk.
Don't push yourself.
I want to walk with you.
Yeah?
Then let's walk together as far as you can.
Yup.
Let's go!
Let's make this a fun trip.
Ya!
Are you all right, Ushio?
Yup.
You have to let me know the moment you're not feeling well.
We'll go to a doctor then.
Yup.
Ushio...
Let's...
It's snowing.
Do you like snow, Ushio?
Yup.
Do you like it, too?
I...
Yeah, I like it, too.
Can you keep walking, Ushio?
Do you want to rest a little?
No.
Let's get in a car before it starts coming down hard.
I'll give you a piggy back ride.
I'm fine.
Ushio!
Daddy...
What is it, Ushio?
Where are we?
Are we on the train?
Yeah. We're on the train already.
It's dark... Is it night?
That's right. It's midnight.
Oh...
Daddy?
I love you.
Yeah.
I love you, too, Ushio.
Ushio?
Ushio!
USHIO!
No...
I don't want this.
Nagisa...
Save Ushio.
Nagisa!
Someone... Someone save Ushio!
Nagisa...
Thank you.
How many more steps will it take to get there?
Could we be only a step away?
Or, do we have to walk without end?
I hate this city.
It's full of all the memories I want to forget about.
Go to school every day, chat with friends, and then go back to the home I don't even want to go back to.
Will something eventually change, doing this?
Will that day come?
Sweet bean bread!
Do you like this school?
I really, really love it.
But nothing can stay unchanged.
If I talk to her here, Nagisa and I
will meet and eventually date.
But, maybe it was better if I didn't.
It might've been better if we'd never met.
To be Continued
Preview
Episode 22
The Palm of a Tiny Hand