We were standing outside the house.
Don't go too far.
Or else we won't be able to get back home.
This is a world that had ended.
There is no one here other than us.
We were looking for junk that could be useful.
We have to find our own tools for living.
I'll take this.
Let's take this back, too.
Were you scared of being alone?
I'm glad you're back.
Thank you.
It's strange.
They had a gentle smell.
Are you eating at the cafeteria for lunch again?
You just got here, didn't you?
Yeah.
Start right. Otherwise, you'll mess up my rhythm.
Fine. Then I'll start over.
Hello, Okazaki.
Are you eating at the cafeteria for lunch again?
You sound so refreshing.
What?
It's too refreshing coming from you.
You weirded me out with your change in character.
Then what am I supposed to do?!
At the end of the sentence, always add the phrase, "and a toilet seat cover".
That will counter the freshness and make you sound more like yourself.
All right.
Episode 2
In Search of a Fake Love
I'll do it one of these days when I feel like it.
What? Mei's staying over at Nagisa-chan's again?
We're perfectly happy having her.
Since we all love Mei-chan.
She called ahead and let her parents and school know.
Apparently she's worried about you.
Onii-chan's a senior, and it's the second semester, yet he still doesn't know what he'll be doing.
I'm so worried I can't go home.
She said she wants to have a good talk with you later.
Sunohara-san. Do you have a goal or something you want to do?
I've never thought about it.
I can't go to college, so I'll find a job and work.
Well, if I had a level-headed girlfriend, too,
I bet my sister would rest easier.
That's it!
Basically, we'll show her that you have
a girlfriend who you've sworn your life to.
I'm sure Mei-chan will stop worrying that way.
I don't think you should tell her a lie.
Would something like that work?
So you know, you're actually not that ugly.
You've got a baby face, so you're the type that tickles the maternal instinct.
This school's number one baby face.
Baby Sunohara.
Y-You think so?
You might end up dating the fake girlfriend for real with this as a start.
Okazaki magic, eh?
I'm starting to get fired up!
Tomoya-kun. Aren't you just having fun?
Not at all.
Are there any obedient girls who'll probably listen to me?
You're really underhanded, you know.
I found a perfect candidate!
Go!
Wait!
You're going to ask her?!
You don't have to be that surprised.
Pretend. It's just pretend.
If you can't, you can say no.
Since you know well what kind of a guy he is.
I can't. It's impossible.
It's too much for me.
Just thinking about it is so embarrassing...
I can't possibly...
Please don't cry, Ryou-chan.
When you see something like this,
doesn't it make you want to keep going?
Hey. If you say something like that...
Are you all right, Ryou?
Was he picking on you?
I'm all right.
It wasn't anything like that.
You two. What did you do to my cute sister?!
You misunderstand, Kyou-chan.
We're actually looking for
a fake girlfriend for Sunohara-san.
How about we try asking Kyou?
I doubt she'd say yes.
Yeah, given her character...
Vicious and hot-headed, says
unreasonable things and uses me like a slave.
I can hear everything you're saying, you know?
You care to repeat those words?
If you do, I'll stick my hand down your throat and rip out your vocal cords as a reward.
I-I'm sorry.
I apologized, didn't I?!
Your apologizing face pissed me off for some reason.
Let's go, Ryou.
Their idiocy will infect us if we stay.
Okay...
Why do guys lack delicacy so much?
I'll see you later.
Are you really all right, Sunohara-san?
Don't worry. He shines brightest when he's being picked on by girls.
Don't say things that'll cause misunderstandings!
But with both Fujibayashi and Kyou down, who else might say yes?
How about asking Tomoyo-san?
Are you serious?
She's beautiful and takes good care of others.
I think she's a nice person.
We'd better not.
He's wimping out, too.
Don't be an idiot! Who's w-wimping out?!
You had an extra "w" there.
Take a deep breath and calm down first.
Okay. I'm ready to give birth to a good kid.
Sunohara-san, you're panicking.
If you think about it, she and I are fated rivals.
We would fight every time we bumped into each other.
What's wrong? You seem troubled; that's unlike you.
It's got nothing to do with you.
I guess you're right.
But...
I don't want to see you lose to anyone other then me.
Deep down, there's mutual respect between those who recognize each other's strength.
It's so touching!
Therefore I'm going!
Tea stains are actually tannin.
Baking soda is often used to wash them off.
If you don't have any-
If you don't have any, vinegar should be fine, too.
Don't ignore me like that!
Sakagami-san, you know him?
Stay away. It's dangerous to make eye contact with him.
Don't talk of me like I'm an animal!
Tomoyo-san. Please listen to what he has to say.
Oh, Furukawa-san.
Yesterday's baseball game was fun, wasn't it?
Yes.
You looked really cool.
It's actually my first time calling you Furukawa-san, isn't it?
Was that all right?
Of course.
I'm happy.
Could you two not carry on a conversation without me?!
What, you were still here?
He has a favor to ask. Could you hear him out?
You guys come asking for favors a lot, don't you?
I'm really troubled right now, you know?
You look carefree to me, as you always do.
It's got nothing to do with you.
Exactly. See you.
No! You're supposed to say, "I don't want to see you lose to anyone other then me."
I've never considered saying that in my life, not even the slightest bit.
Just say it! Or else we can't advance the story!
I don't want to see you lose to anyone other than me.
"Lose"? Who?
How about we-
If he wanted to fight, he should have said so immediately.
See you, Okazaki.
Furukawa-san, too.
That was so cool.
As expected of Sakagami-san.
Okay. I'll help.
Seriously?!
You're so kind, Kotomi-chan.
I want to be of help to my friend.
Tell me what I should do.
If you're dating, I think you would hang out and do all sorts of fun things together.
That's right.
What should we do?
Then...
Look at what you made her do!
Didn't the violin get fixed?!
Yes. It makes better sound than before.
It's actually gotten worse!
Was it really all right, Sunohara-san?
She agreed to act for you.
I don't have the willpower to make it through that sound.
Don't give up.
We still have one hope.
Miyazawa, are you here?
Okazaki-san, Furukawa-san, Sunohara-san.
Long time no see.
Yes, it has been a while, Miyazawa-san.
Yukine-chan, eh?
Yeah, you look like you'll do anything.
What is this about?
To act as a girlfriend, is it?
It sounds difficult.
That's not true!
I'll lead you along well.
So please. Yeah?
I've been listening for a while...
Who do you think you are to ask such a thing of our Yuki-nee?!
"Our Yuki-nee?"
Miyazawa-san, who is this person?
He's my guest.
There is a small issue, so he is hiding here.
Let me tell you clearly!
If you cause any trouble for Yuki-nee, we won't let you live.
Do you hear?!
Crap, I wasn't supposed to come out.
Yuki-nee, if anything happens, call me.
I'll dash over.
You shouldn't go out yet.
You need to hide.
I'm sorry, I need to excuse myself.
What was that about?
Looks like she has some things to deal with, too.
I'm going to leave you two here.
I have to help make dinner.
Good luck, Sunohara-san.
"Good luck" she says, but...
It wasn't right to ask for free.
Let's put out a reward.
I don't have any money.
That doesn't matter, since you're going to charm her, anyway, right?
That's right.
First, you have to flatter the girl.
And, girls these days like to keep secrets,
so let her know that secrets are safe with you.
Lastly, using group psychology to your advantage, appeal saying that everyone does it.
Got it.
I'm off then.
Hey there cutie!
What?
Do you have some time right now?
It'd be great if you would even just listen to what I need to say.
I actually have a good part-time job for you.
I'm in a hurry.
I won't say your name.
And I'll keep it a secret to your parents, too.
Don't worry. Everyone's doing it.
That makes me sound like I'm scouting her for something sketchy!
Um...
Sanae-san!
Are you having some trouble?
Oh.
If that's the case, would you allow me to help?
Are you serious, Sanae-san?
It's for none other than Mei-chan's brother's sake.
If I can be of help, then I'll gladly do so.
W-W-Wait a moment.
Okazaki. She's Nagisa-chan's older sister, right?
Sister?
Ah, right. I said something like that yesterday, didn't I?
Crap! As expected from Nagisa-chan's sister!
She's so freaking hot when I see her up close.
This is interesting, so I'll let him keep thinking wrong.
Um...
Would I not be suitable?
That's not true at all!
But wouldn't it be too obvious that you're a fake girlfriend?
It'll be all right. I'll go in a disguise.
Then you're serious?
Yes. I look forward to acting with you.
Yahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
You have a girlfriend?!
Someone I've sworn my future to.
She's really beautiful and level-headed.
I'm not living aimlessly.
I'm walking up the stairs to adulthood one step at a time.
Let me see her.
Introduce me to her.
As your younger sister, I want to know what kind of person you're going to marry!
Okay. Then I'll ask her what her schedule's like.
The Theater Club has many costumes, doesn't it?
You'll meet Mei-chan the day after tomorrow.
So tomorrow will be a practice run.
Okay. I'm looking forward to it.
It feels complicated to me.
My mom is my classmate's girlfriend...
Are you really sure about this?
Sunohara's really hyped over this.
He thinks of you as Nagisa's older sister.
Sister?
Thank you very much.
I wasn't trying to flatter you...
Shouldn't you reconsider this, Mom?
Sunohara-san has been on
my mind since the baseball game.
He looks clumsy and makes many mistakes, but I think he's actually a very kind person.
With a push, I think he can start walking a better path.
I want to help him get there.
Okay. If you think so, then I'll help, too.
Yes. Thank you very much.
Let me say one thing.
We need to keep this a secret from the old man.
Okay?
Why?
Sanae-san might be doing it for the sake of helping others,
but knowing him, he might fly into
a jealous rage and turn Sunohara into mincemeat.
For Sunohara's safety, we need to keep this a secret.
Sunohara-san's really nervous.
Watching him is pissing me off.
Why?
Don't tell me you're in love with Mom, too.
You idiot! What are you saying?!
Um...
Y-Yes!
It would be strange to call you "Sunohara-kun" when we're dating, so I'll call you "Youhei-kun".
Y-Y-Y-Yeah?
Youhei-kun.
I look forward to spending time with you.
Crap! She called me "Youhei-kun"!
Shall we begin with walking next to each other?
Y-Y-Y-Yes!
You can come closer.
Since we're dating.
Crap! I smelled something sweet!
How about we hold hands, too?
Crap! They're so soft!
Don't come reporting to me each time.
Is that really making him go down the right path?
It feels complicated to me, after all...
And so the day comes.
Sunohara-san's here already.
Mei-chan, call out to him from behind.
I bet he'll think it's his girl and be surprised.
Then I'll give it a little try.
Did you wait long?
No, I just got here.
MEI?!
Sunohara-san, what are all of these cans?
This is part of my strategy.
She'll see this when she gets here, right?
Then...
Sunohara-san...
You waited for me this long?
You see how it goes?
You're really underhanded.
This is the game in the name of love guys play.
In other words, it's a boy love game.
So you know, that implies something different.
Crap. I drank too much and nature calls.
If it's this messy, it'll be a bother, right?
Yeah.
Let's clean it up.
Yes.
Let me help, too.
Thank you.
It's nothing.
This is rather...
Tomoya-kun, are you blushing?
That felt good.
Youhei-kun.
I'm sorry! Did I make you wait?!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Not at all. I just arrived.
This person is my brother's girlfriend?
To be Continued
Preview
Enjoy your time with her.
Hold on, Mei.
Y-Yeah, but I shouldn't go in case Sanae-san calls.
But love is a person's choice.
Wait...
Episode 3
Hearts that do not Converge