You worked really well today.
What?
You learn things fast and do them right, too.
You could be well-suited for this kind of job.
Could it be... Are you complimenting me?
Don't get let it get to your head, though.
We're doing the same thing every day,
so of course you'd improve.
Right.
All those people I studied with back then went to college and must be in some city.
I'm here alone.
But I'm not by myself.
There are people who get covered in dirt and grime every day like me.
It's the new place I've chosen and have earned.
Now, here's a quiz.
Thank you.
Here he goes again.
Which of the following is this summer's first big event I came up with?
One: BBQ at the Beach.
Two: RIP at the Beach
Three: Barbara Fujioka at the Beach.
They all sound so similar.
The last one was completely different.
The "bar" sound is the same!
You go play with Barbara Fujioka alone!
Who is that, anyway?
I haven't had a chance to play with Nagisa, so I'm lonely.
I don't care what it is; I just want some time with her.
I'm sorry.
It's natural for you two to spend a lot of time together, but it's hard to let go of one's child.
I see.
Is it something like that?
Episode 12
A Sudden Happening
Your place is really lively as always.
What's on your mind?
Um, there's something I want to talk to you about.
What? You want a swimsuit?
No, it's not that.
Oh, but it's not that I don't want one.
All right then. I get out early tomorrow, so let's go buy one tomorrow evening.
What? Is that all right?
I bet you only have a school swimsuit, right?
Yes. But I don't mind that at all.
I do.
After all, you want to see your girlfriend looking cute.
Be the beach queen.
What? Me in a swimsuit is...
Don't say that. We'll have fun shopping tomorrow.
Yes.
All right, then-
That's not what I wanted to say.
It wasn't a swimsuit?
Then-
Tomoya-kun.
Tomoya-kun, have you met with
your father properly after you've moved?
Have you told him your new address?
No.
You know that there's a distance between me and him.
It's a distance that can never be closed.
But!
I'm working every day.
I'm working until I'm completely exhausted.
I want to be with you at least on my days off.
I don't want to do anything unpleasant.
It doesn't have to be now.
Let's go meet him together one day.
Yeah.
One day.
Yes. One day.
My old colleague is working as an assistant director with the principal contractor.
He's looking for a young person who can manage a site.
I see.
First as a trainee,
but of course eventually as full staff.
They said they'll pay... about this much, too.
That's amazing.
And I'm thinking of recommending you.
Would you be interested in going?
W-Wait a moment please. Are you firing me?!
Don't get it wrong.
He's recommending you because he cares.
I won't ask you to make a decision now.
But I hope you would give it some thought.
Yes...
What's there to hesitate over?
But I was thinking of building my career at this company.
Besides, you're more of an immediate help than me.
I'm bad at socializing.
I can be a technician but can't be a manager.
You're younger, so you have more potential.
But this is too sudden.
If you take the offer, your pay will go up.
You'll eventually be supporting a family, too.
Right?
If there's someone important to you, then it's not too difficult to overcome several obstacles.
Did you start working here thinking things like that?
I'm sorry. That was a personal question.
You want to hear an old story?
A story of a boy who sang rock in this city before.
He had done whatever he wanted since he was little.
Nobody ever yelled at him,
so he was always doing bad things.
Back then, the band scene was booming.
So he picked up a guitar, too.
Like running up on other people's stages and stealing the mike away.
He was being ridiculous.
When he was a senior in high school, he met a woman.
She said she liked the love song he sang.
It had embarrassing lyrics,
but she earnestly read the meaning.
Though, she was a clumsy one, for example,
she forgot she was in the middle of heading to class because she talked for too long.
After graduation, he was planning to live on music.
Everyone in class laughed at him, but that teacher encouraged him.
She said, "As long as you continue, it will come true, so don't give up."
On the day he left, he said,
"I'll definitely become a professional! If I do, please go out with me!"
He etched in his heart that he would become a professional.
The debut came pretty fast.
"Take that!"
He wanted to say that to all those who had made fun of him.
From that day on, he worked frantically.
He sang what he wanted with everything he had.
Like spitting out.
Like vomiting.
At times, he sang ugly lines, too.
But when he sang with everything he had, it sounded beautiful.
Living really felt refreshing.
Because to live was the ugliest act.
He had found his place.
One day, a project was brought in from a TV station.
It was to meet fans of his.
Not just any fans.
Fans that had been saved by his music and were still facing adversity.
Those who were sick.
Those who had gotten in accidents.
Those who were going through tremendous hardship because of their parents.
Those who had weak minds and were about to break down at any moment.
They all stood in the midst of suffering.
They all used his songs for support.
It was a moment he knew his song no longer belonged only to him.
Until that day, he had only sung for himself.
But that was no longer true.
He had to start composing for thousands of people he had never even met before.
He became unable to compose music.
Because he had learned...
...the grandeur of life...
...his shallowness...
...and his insignificance.
The agency told him to take a vacation.
And six months later...
Year Old Arrested for Assault
Trouble between friends?
A boy he had met through the TV program committed a crime.
A huge crime that couldn't be forgiven.
Everything fell apart from there.
The one who had committed the crime was...
Mysterious motive! Conflicting friendship?
...the one who said, "Listening to your songs calms my heart."
"I want to hear your new song soon," the boy had said, speaking more enthusiastically than others.
He thought everything was his fault.
He thought he had taken away
the boy's reason to live by not singing.
He started singing again.
He sang of the impossible and ideals,
thinking that would save those who waited for him.
He didn't have a clue why he was singing such words himself.
But he continued to sing, ignoring the doubts.
The songs eventually deviated from ideals and began to be echoes of a sick reality.
Only realistic pain could be attained from the song.
The lyrics didn't make any sense.
They contradicted each other.
Even then, he continued to sing...
...because he feared the loss of singing the most.
Then...
He resorted to the worst choice.
It was an unforgivable mistake.
Famous Rock
Yoshino
Yusuke
suspect
No place was left for him after committing the crime.
With nothing to rely on, in the depths of desperation, he made one wish.
"I want to go home."
Are you keeping up with music?
Everything had changed.
It couldn't have stayed the same.
As long as you continue, it will come true.
There was something he never should have lost sight of.
He should have continued singing.
Not for anyone else, but for her.
The love songs for her.
Hey, we're here.
That's the end of the story.
Let's go.
Ah, yes.
Okazaki.
Yes!
Don't lose track of what's important to you.
Yes.
I see.
I think you should choose the path you think is best.
Yeah.
I'll be transferred to another office, but you won't stop me, huh?
I won't, since it's proof that they've recognized how hard you've been working.
I see.
Yeah.
All right. Let's do it.
Yup.
Bring it on!
You won't play with him?
No, I'm all right.
You'd rather be with your girlfriend than play with children, right?
Really, look at how beautiful Nagisa-chan has become.
Yes, thank you very much.
You look just like me when I was young.
Oh, come on.
Tomorrow's the beach, huh?
It's been a while.
I think you look kinder now, too.
You were talking with a smile to other people, too.
Very naturally at that, too.
I always thought things like that were annoying.
And I say this when at school, I stuck my nose into other people's business so much.
You don't feel that way now?
Nagisa.
Sure.
May I pick it up?
Yeah, thanks.
Yes, this is Okazaki.
Yes. Please hold a moment.
Tomoya-kun. It's from Hikarizaka Electric.
Maybe the transfer went through.
Hello, Okazaki speaking.
Ah, good evening, Manager.
From Kinoshita-san?
Ah, yes. What's his phone number?
Yes. Yes...
Yes. Thank you very much.
Yes. Good night.
Tomoya-kun?
They got a call from my pop's acquaintance.
I wonder what it could be about.
Yes, this is Kinoshita.
Hi, this is Okazaki.
Oh, Tomoya-kun? We've got some trouble!
Your father got arrested by the police.
Apparently he was dealing with some dangerous stuff.
I heard the story and figured I had to get in contact with you.
It's a small city, so rumors spread fast, too.
Sorry, but they want to cancel the deal.
I see.
But of course, continue to work here like you have been.
I guess things just happened at a bad time.
Hold the course.
Nagisa.
Yes?
Do you want to leave this city together?
I realized from this event.
I'm cursed by him.
I want to start over in a place where his curse won't reach me.
I...
I won't.
That's just running away!
You can't run away from something like this.
I want you to make me have a happy life...
...in this city.
I can make that happen away from this city!
You won't say that I'm all you need?
I would go anywhere if you're there.
But we have to leave this city on a positive note if we are leaving.
Otherwise, this place won't become a place to come back to.
This is the city in which we were born.
It's our city.
Even if there's nothing good about this place?
I had many good things.
The best is that I met you.
You...
What do you want?!
Is it fun ruining other people's lives?
I don't consider you my parent.
But society doesn't think that.
I'm your son.
You don't even have anything to say?
Don't you have anything to say to your son who you've caused so many problems for?
Stop screwing with me!
Tomoya-kun!
That's enough. I've got nothing more to say to him.
Live like that forever!
Tomoya-kun.
Please wait!
What are you doing?!
You can't!
Tomoya-kun!
Does your hand hurt?
Yeah.
I'm sure it'll sting when you get in the bath.
I bet.
Nagisa.
Yes?
Let's get married.
Yes.
Are you sure?
I've always been thinking that you're the only one.
I'm a guy like this!
I'm a really pathetic...
I am, too.
But if we're together, we can become strong.
Will you always be with me?
Yes.
I will always be with you.
No matter when.
No matter how long.
To be Continued
Preview
I'm sorry for worrying you.
Please! No one was bothered by it.
Neither Nagisa, me, nor Akio-san was.
But society is.
As proof, I lost a position due to this.
But there's more than one path to take.
He really is like me.
I was frantic to become an adult.
Episode 13
Graduation
And I was still just a kid then, too.