Nagisa, can I have your autograph while I have the chance?
What doting parents.
Same thing will happen to you once you have a daughter, too.
I swear it won't.
I can see you having one,
since you are very much like Dad.
What? Me and him?!
Two months, eh?
Yes, it's been two months.
You will have the baby, right?
Of course.
It's a piece of work, you know?
I'll protect her.
Tomoya-kun will be there for me, so I'll be all right.
We worked together until today.
He looks just like you on that day, Akio-san.
When I had Nagisa in my stomach, you said that you'd protect her.
I did, didn't I?
Good luck, you bum.
"Bum..."
But I'm not allowed to be one anymore.
Nagisa will probably have to take a break from work.
I'll have to support three people.
This is where the trial for my family begins.
A thought crossed my mind.
Did my old man think the same thing before I was born?
Congratulations.
What?
I heard you had a baby.
Your wife had a kid?
Congratulations, Mr. Okazaki.
No, it's not born yet.
Yoshino-san, who did you hear it from?
My wife heard it from Sanae-san.
Everyone in the neighborhood knows about it.
To be feared: the power of neighbors.
You've still got a way to go as a member of society,
but now you'll have to act like
a real husband no matter what.
Yeah... but it doesn't feel real to me.
You'll feel that no matter what once the baby's born.
No one in this world can live alone.
Everyone lives by supporting
and being supported by others.
There he goes...
It's been 4.5 billion years since the Earth was formed in this vast universe...
Episode 15
As a Summer Memory
The days started to move at an amazing speed.
By the time she entered the third month, the pregnancy sickness worsened and Nagisa spent most days in bed.
I'm sorry for the trouble.
Don't worry; I can take care of these.
I'm sorry.
Don't apologize.
We're supposed to do this together, aren't we?
Did you eat at all?
I couldn't eat much.
Isn't there any way to make this a little easier for you?
Apparently, it's not even known why pregnancy sickness happens.
Drinking water only makes me sick, so I take these to get water.
It tastes good.
Oh, sorry. Did I wake you up?
How are you feeling?
I'm feeling all right now.
That's great.
You should eat some, even a little, while you can.
What do you think?
Did you make these?
I'm not used to it, so the shape is a little... you know...
Thank you very much. I'll have some.
It's good!
While the days went flying by,
Nagisa and I were restless.
Good morning.
Is it all right for you to be up?
I feel very good today.
The doctor said that things will stabilize around the tenth week.
He was exactly right.
Must mean it's growing well.
Yes. I'm glad.
Um, I have something I wanted to talk about.
Give birth at home?
Yes. I want to give birth to the baby here.
Can you even do such a thing?
I got this pamphlet for a maternity class yesterday at the hospital.
There's a page by a mother who gave birth at home.
So the father gives the first bath, eh?
At a hospital, there are cases where you can't hold the baby immediately.
I would like to be able to.
This is your and my house.
I want to give birth to the baby in our home. In this city.
What do you think?
Give birth at home?!
How was that drift?
How about you turn off the game?
You know, giving birth is hard enough,
and  you're gonna try to pull it off at your home?
The doctor is worried about Nagisa's health,
but I want to fulfill Nagisa's wishes as much as possible.
That said, of course it's a question of how well she is at the time.
You're right. Having a safe delivery is the most important thing.
But when I gave birth to Nagisa, I was soon separated from her.
Akio-san held Nagisa after the doctors, too.
But I was the first one to lick you.
You licked me?!
You were that cute.
You can't do such a thing even if I was cute!
Too late now.
So you agree to giving birth at home?
If there's nothing to worry about, physically, then why not.
Make sure you give the first hug.
But...
I'll be the first to lick!
No. Tomoya-kun also gets the first lick!
No, I won't be licking.
Ah, right. He won't be.
What a stupid family.
This is Yagi-san.
She is my friend and works as a midwife.
I'm Yagi. Nice to meet you.
I'm Okazaki Nagisa.
Thank you for coming.
I'm her husband, Tomoya.
I was told you were looking into delivering the baby here.
Yes.
Can it be done in a place like this?
What's important is to be in a place where you can relax.
There's still time.
Please take the time to think things through.
We'll be in your care.
If anything happens, please let me know any time.
Thank you very much.
Yagi-san knows that Nagisa has a weak body.
If those around worry about it too much, the mother becomes uneasy, too, so I was told to be mindful of that.
Okay.
What were you talking about with Mom?
Um... Nothing in particular.
You don't need to hide it; it was about my health, right?
I know how you, Mom, and Dad are all worried about it.
But, even if the worst happens to me,
I want to give birth to the baby.
Don't say such a thing.
We're all working so you have a safe delivery.
You're right. I'm sorry.
Doesn't this remind you of our high school days?
What?
Remember how we all worked together to make the stage a success?
I just thought that it's like that.
Can you tell? I'm your daddy.
You can't tell lies like that; the baby will believe you.
Your kid can't even take a joke?
It's Nagisa's baby, so it probably can't,
Gramps.
Don't call me that!
Apparently Akio-san wants to be called "Akki".
Hey, it's Akki. I'm Akki.
Quit the prenatal training.
The ears are there by this time,
and it can hear the sounds from the outside,
so it's good to let it listen to music.
I'm always singing songs to it.
Dango, dango, dango, dango,
Big Dango Family.
I thought everything was going well.
Or, perhaps somewhere in my heart,
I was eagerly anticipating that day coming.
I'm home.
Nagisa!
I'm all right.
I just got a little sick.
Nagisa called in the afternoon.
I rushed over, and Nagisa was on the floor.
Then you could have told me, too.
I'm sorry; I didn't want to disturb you at work.
Please don't worry; the baby's well.
I see.
Call me at any time anything happens.
To be on the safe side, I'll be with Nagisa during the day from tomorrow on.
That way you'll rest easy, right, Tomoya-san?
Yes. Thank you very much.
How are you feeling? Is there anything you want?
I don't need anything.
I'm at ease when you're by my side.
Of course. Since you're strong, right?
Please don't worry, Tomoya-kun.
No, I wasn't...
I'm sure we can make it through if we're together, since I'm being protected by you.
Nagisa.
But...
I was no longer able to relax in the blessed feeling.
Tomoya-san.
Oh, Sanae-san.
Welcome home.
So this is where Nagisa was working.
I wanted to come here once, too.
It's a very trendy place.
No one uses that word nowadays.
Is that so?
I have something I need to tell you.
Yes?
It's about Nagisa.
I was told by the doctor that there will be some danger during the delivery.
I have not told this to Nagisa yet.
Only I've been told.
Exactly how much danger is there?
Don't say even Nagisa's life is at...
The stress to the mother will be greater than an average delivery's,
but there shouldn't be any problem with the delivery itself.
I see.
However that's if everything goes well.
As you know, Nagisa falls ill from time to time.
There are many mysterious aspects to Nagisa's illness,
and the doctors are worried about the worst-case scenario, as well.
This is something that needs to be thought through carefully.
That's why I wanted to tell you first.
You should tell Nagisa, and both of you should go listen to what the doctor has to say.
After that, let's all think together.
If we think of the worst-case scenario,
should we give up on having the child?
I cannot answer that.
But, if that's the choice to make, then the sooner the better.
Please think it through carefully with Nagisa.
Sanae-san, as always, thank you.
We're a family, right?
I want to have the baby.
I knew you would say that.
I am a weak person, but I don't want to give up on the baby because of that.
If it's to have the baby, then I don't mind giving up on delivering here.
Nagisa...
I want to meet the baby.
What did the doctor say?
They said the risk would go down if she delivered at the hospital.
But I'm still worried.
Nagisa didn't change her mind, right?
No.
I think in her heart, she's scared, too.
She's acting cheerful, but I think she may be feeling the same things as me.
Come with me for a sec.
There!
This is my secret playground.
I play baseball with kids or sit and do nothing here a lot.
I noticed you went missing during work a lot, so this is where you were, huh?
The trees and bushes got torn down one after another...
There!
...and apparently a hospital's going to be built here soon.
Yay!
Sorry!
It's a great thing.
Thank you very much!
This is the continuation of something I told you two years ago.
It's when I was still in theater and Sanae was a teacher.
As I told you, Nagisa was always alone back then.
That day, Sanae and I left for work, leaving the sick Nagisa at home.
We both couldn't skip work.
Nagisa's condition looked stable, and both Sanae and I were planning to come home right away.
Nagisa was outside.
She was waiting until she collapsed.
By the time morning came,
it looked like there was no hope.
I never went through anything that sad.
This will be the first time I've told the story from this point on to anyone but Sanae.
Before I realized it, I was running with Nagisa in my arms.
I was running aimlessly, and I ended up here.
I prayed.
"Please save Nagisa."
"I don't want an ending like this."
All I could do was pray.
Right then, it felt like the plants here covered Nagisa.
I thought I was dreaming.
But it was reality.
Tears overwhelmed me,
and I thanked everything in this world.
I've been looking after this place ever since.
I couldn't help but to think of this place as Nagisa's double.
Strange story, isn't it?
But it really happened.
Yeah. I believe you.
It's impossible for all wishes to come true if you pray for them.
But if you think and put your best effort forth until the end, then the outcome can't be that bad.
You're right.
I'm not telling you to have the baby.
I'm saying leave the judgment to the one who goes through the most pain,
and we'll just accept the result.
Hey, brat.
Or rather, Tomoya.
I'm sure there will be lots of hardships and painful stuff waiting for you ahead.
You guys can...
We can overcome them.
Yeah.
We're a family.
We're going to help each other.
The wind feels nice and cold.
It just moved!
Really?
Yes.
It felt like I was rubbed from the inside.
Really?
How about we come up with a name?
Yeah. We'll need one if it's a boy and another if it's a girl.
How about we use one character from your name?
No, rather than that, let's think of
something from your name.
I can pass on the last name.
But it's difficult to use my name.
It'd become like Nagisako or Nagisami.
You don't have to use it literally.
Something that traces back to Nagisa should do.
I see...
In that case...
How does Ushio sound?
Ushio?
Yes. It's about how the tide rises and goes out.
If it's this, it can be used for a boy or a girl.
Okazaki Ushio, eh?
I'm sure a lot will happen within a life.
But as time passes, things will return to you.
That will continue, and I will watch over Ushio.
Rather than a "nagisa", a bay, "ushio" is more grand, isn't it?
You're right.
Since it's the ocean.
Will it be able to grow up to be someone with the kindness to embrace and nurture anything?
I hope it will.
We couldn't go to the beach again this summer.
You're right.
I wanted to see the ocean with you, too.
Then let's make a promise.
What?
Next year, we'll go to the beach with Ushio.
It's a promise.
A promise...
You will promise to, won't you, Nagisa?
Yes, I promise.
To be Continued
Preview
There may be more than one hidden world.
There's a theory of multiple worlds existing, too.
Fujibayashi.
I remember you saying something like that when you were talking about fortune-telling.
Yes. There is no one future,
but there are many possibilities.
I still think that.
Episode 16
White Darkness