So, what was that about?
What was what about?
Mei-chan's still around, right?
It looked like you two were having fun yesterday.
We spoke about what could be going on after seeing you.
I want to play with Mei-chan, as well.
I want to let her listen to the violin.
I think that's a bad idea.
Kyou-chan's a bully.
Mei-chan's worried about Sunohara-san.
We talked about it last night, but...
But I think that's the only chance.
If he plays soccer again,
maybe he'll return to the way he used to be.
Huh? Talk about the impossible.
There's no way he could return to the soccer team now.
I told her the same thing.
You know well what kind of group our Soccer Team is.
It's best you stay away from them.
Yes, since our school's Soccer Team is a little special.
Are they bullies?
For once, your pet phrase actually fits.
Episode 4
With the Same Smile as That Day
He wasn't in the dorm, either?
No. Even Misae-san doesn't know where he went.
What should we do? Without the actual person, we can't ask them to let him rejoin.
Mei-chan, let's think it over.
I think the chance of this working is slim.
I'll go on ahead and ask them.
"Go ahead", as in to the Soccer Team?
Yes. You two wait here please.
I'll go by myself.
Don't be ridiculous.
How could we let you?
If you're going to go, then we will, too.
Did you just say Sunohara Youhei?
Winter's the critical season for high school soccer, right?
Even a senior should be able to participate.
Could you let him play again?
Shut your trap.
We don't even want to hear his name.
Get lost.
Um!
My name is Mei, Sunohara Youhei's younger sister.
Sunohara's younger sister?
I'm aware how my brother has caused trouble to you all.
But please!
At this rate, I think he will become a loafer.
So!
He was a loafer to begin with.
Yeah. A loafer will always be
a loafer no matter what he does.
Okazaki. You're the same as him,
so don't you understand that logic?
And you, too.
You're repeating a grade and are an outcast, too, right?
Loafers should hang out with loafers.
Tomoya-kun.
Sorry. I should have gone there alone first.
I'm sorry, too.
Both of you had to suffer because of me.
No, we're fine. Rather...
Would you like another cup, Mei-chan?
Yes, thank you very much.
Sorry we're imposing on you.
I had a feeling you would listen to something like this.
I'm completely fine.
Since I have guests with an assortment of problems needing advice come here often.
Okazaki-san.
If it's all right, would you share what happened between Sunohara-san and the Soccer Team?
Can I, Mei-chan?
He started a fight when he was a freshman.
Our school's Soccer Team has a tradition of underclassmen being hazed by upperclassmen.
The hierarchy within the team is atrocious.
Apparently Sunohara couldn't stand that.
The first time I met him was then.
I got in a fight somewhere else and bumped into him near the faculty room, and we've been hanging out since.
I never knew that part.
Because of the fight, the team had to withdraw from the rookie tournament that year.
Sunohara left the team afterwards.
So the Soccer Team hasn't forgotten what happened then.
If so, would Sunohara-san be able to enjoy playing soccer in an environment like that?
I don't know.
But soccer's the only way to get Onii-chan back to who he used to be.
But there's no point in us getting worked up when he's not around.
He's so hopeless.
Have I ever told you the story of my older brother?
You have an older brother, too?
My brother would not go to school; instead he'd loiter around party town and constantly get into fights.
He was detained by the police several times, too.
Your brother was?
I never would have guessed.
Siblings can be strange.
But you like your brother, right?
I used to think of him as a scary person, but I understand him well now.
He has many good traits
but just can't express them well.
He was simply clumsy.
Sanae-san described Sunohara like that, too, didn't she?
I think, too, that Sunohara-san has many good traits.
Even if it's not with soccer, given the chance, he'll be the brother you used to love again.
What is it like now between you and your brother?
We get along very well.
Sunohara, what were you doing yesterday?
It's my business what I do.
You don't care about what Mei-chan's doing?
Why are you even asking that?
Mei was with you, right?
I'm busy taking care of matters with Sanae-san.
I don't have time to worry about Mei.
Do you seriously mean that?
Yeah.
I'll leave Mei to you.
Make sure you take good care of her.
You'd better quit it now.
What are you angry about?
I bet Mei doesn't care about me either.
SUNOHARA!!!
Okazaki-kun! Sunohara-kun!
What do you think Mei-chan's doing now?
I don't know.
But I bet you and her are having a good time together.
Ask the Soccer Team yourself!
They'll tell you how much she's thinking about you!
What are you talking about?
You're not making any sense.
Please stop, Okazaki-kun!
What happened?
You wanna fight, Okazaki?
Break it up!
What's this about? What's the reason for this?
What happened, Ryou-chan?
I'm not sure, either.
Tomoya-kun, Sunohara-kun.
I don't think fighting is good.
Tomoya.
Tomoya-kun.
Sunohara-kun, really, what is the matter here?
So you got in a fight?
Yeah. I lost my head.
What's Onii-chan doing now?
He skipped afternoon classes.
He must have gone out to play.
I see.
Are you going to the Soccer Team again?
Yes. After hearing Miyazawa-san's story, I feel like I have to keep trying harder.
I can go alone, really.
I can't trouble you any more with this sibling matter.
It's no trouble at all.
No. Nagisa, you go on home.
Why?
You know what kind of a bunch the Soccer Team is.
We don't know how the meeting may get twisted.
Just Mei-chan and I should go.
I won't allow that!
I can't let just the two of you go after hearing that.
What would you do if they started to get violent?
If it turns into a fight, I won't be able to cover you.
If that happens, I'll run away with Mei-chan.
Even if anything were to happen to you,
if I'm there, I can get Mei-chan out of trouble.
You really are stubborn when it comes to something like this.
You guys really don't give up.
We're asking knowing it's impossible.
Please let Sunohara-san back on the team!
It's fine if he can't play in the games.
Just letting him participate in practice is enough.
Hey! Do you see anything in it for us?
We'll just get an extra obstacle on the team.
If there's anything I can help with, please let me!
I'll do anything!
Captain, let's start practicing already.
Forget about them and please get over here.
Yeah.
Please wait!
We know we're being unreasonable.
But please!
We're begging you!
Wow.
I never imagined Okazaki would beg like this.
I heard that you'd changed recently, but I guess the rumor was true.
Okazaki-san...
Go be a ball boy.
Thank you very much!
Thank you very much, Okazaki-san!
That was very admirable of you, Tomoya-kun.
It wasn't much.
Rather than that, let's do our best as ball boys.
Yes!
Don't overexert yourself, since you're not very strong.
I'll be fine.
Please watch out for Mei-chan over me.
Go get it, ball boy!
I'll go!
Don't space out, ball boy!
Yes!
Get a move on, airhead!
You dumbass!
Bring it back here!
I'm sorry!
There goes another!
Come on! Hurry and go get it!
Yes!
Move faster!
Tomoya-kun.
They're doing it on purpose.
What's wrong? Tired already?
Nagisa, Mei-chan, are you all right?
Yes.
I'm fine, too.
You guys catch your breath!
Mei-chan!
Mei-chan.
Those guys...
No. It's because I wasn't paying attention.
Mei-chan, you should...
I'm fine.
That was nothing.
Stop wasting time, trash!
Yes!
We're done.
Good work.
Um, where did the other members go?
They went home.
Practice is over.
We'll listen to what you guys have to say for them.
So, what did you guys want?
About my brother, Sunohara Youhei.
We would like you to let him back on the team.
Ah, sorry. Don't think so.
Who would let a pest like your brother onto the team?
He is a wuss, after all.
A loser that just barks when he's got no balls to do anything.
A dropout that quit soccer and can't study for beans either.
Where's the reason in helping a piece of trash like him?
How could you...
You guys!
Did you guys know that Sunohara knows what you guys are doing?
Apparently he asked one of our younger guys.
But so what?
Your brother didn't show up at all.
You've been ignored.
Despite what his sister's doing for him, he got scared of us and ran away.
He is a hopeless piece of shit.
Mei-chan.
Aw, you made her cry.
You're becoming an eyesore now. Go home!
No... No...
Onii-chan will come.
He'll definitely come.
What won't come won't come.
He will. Onii-chan will.
He'll definitely come save Mei.
Mei-chan.
Huh? Is she an absolute moron?
She is Sunohara's sister, after all.
Here, come on.
If you don't scream louder,
your dear Onii-chan won't hear you.
It hurts!
Stop it!
You bastards!
Hold it.
You want to start a fight with all of us?
Cry louder.
Th-That hurts!
You scum.
Tomoya-kun!
Sorry, Nagisa. I was planning on holding it in for Mei-chan's sake, but I'm at my limits!
Onii-chan!
Come on! Cry!
Don't make Mei cry!
I won't forgive anyone who makes Mei cry!
Why you!
Onii-chan!
Sunohara-san!
Nagisa, take care of Mei-chan!
Yes!
Onii-chan! Onii-chan!
Don't forget I'm here, too!
You guys are insane...
They've got crazy eyes!
Okazaki... Did we win?
I don't know.
But I don't think we lost.
You idiot.
Who are you calling an idiot?
Who else other than you?
Apologize to Mei-chan.
Why?
This never would have happened if you'd kept yourself right.
You really are a worthless brother.
Are you picking a fight with me?
Basically.
Tomoya-kun!
Sunohara-san!
Stop! Please stop!
You flaming idiot!
Do you have any clue what Mei-chan went through because of you?!
You have to be the one to look after her!
Why you...
You're Mei-chan's brother!
Think more of Mei-chan!
I did!
Don't lie to me!
She was hooking up to a guy like me,
and you didn't do anything!
You didn't worry about her!
I did.
I sure did!
Then why did you leave her?!
If you have an excuse, say it!
I thought it was fine if it's you!
I was planning on hiding and watching to the end.
But because you were being so pathetic, I had to come out!
Tomoya-kun! Sunohara-san!
Please stop it!
You should have protected Mei!
Isn't that the boyfriend's role?!
You...
Sunohara!
You love Mei enough to break up with Nagisa-chan, right?
Then get your goddamn act together!
Onii-chan! Okazaki-san!
Please stop this, both of you!
Nagisa-chan? Why are you here?
You've done it now!
Stop it! Please stop it now, Onii-chan!
Onii-chan! Onii-chan!
I'm sorry... I'm sorry...
Mei...
Shouldn't you take a day off from school?
Don't worry. Aren't you the one who's still tired?
No. I'm fine.
What happened to your eyes?
They look horrible.
But they look like they're having fun.
We got a letter from Mei-chan.
Not just a phone call, but a letter?
She really has a keen sense of duty.
She asked me to take care of you.
And she also said she wants to find great friends just like us.
Yeah, it's often said that you're forever stuck with the friends you make during your school days.
I bet now's the only time you can do stupid things like this.
Probably.
Just six more months left at this high school, eh?
There's the old man.
Crap. I'm starting to get really nervous.
Do you want to stop?
No, I won't.
Since the only woman I love is Sanae-san.
Okay. Good luck.
Father!
Oh, ah... Sunohara, right?
What? Are you here to buy bread?
Father! Please give Sanae-san to me!
What's going on, Akio-san?
"Akio-san"?
Tomoya-kun, you haven't told Sunohara-san about Mom yet?
"M-Mom"?
What's the meaning of this?
Akio-san is my husband.
You sunuva... You dare touch my woman?!
Hold it right there!
I was remembering the first time I met Sunohara.
He was a weird blond guy.
I cracked up just looking at his face.
It was my first time laughing so much since coming to this school.
I wanted to try doing stupid things with him.
From the day we met, we've hung out ever since.
And even now...
We're still smiling.
Preview
Yeah, what a coincidence.
You know, if you don't mind-
Who's he?
Looks like he's from a different school.
...because of you, he misunderstood!
There are a lot of guys who are fans of yours in my class, too.
It's great that I'm liked,
but I don't know what they see in a woman who only yells.
In this dirty boy's dorm,
you've become an idol-like figure.
Like a jewel in a dunghill.
Episode 5
The Days You Were There