I-
I love you, Okazaki-kun!
Please date me!
Um...
I'm sorry. You wouldn't know what to do
even if I say something like this, would you?
But it hurts not to say it.
Ah... You know.
Yes?
Thanks. But we only recently started to get to know one another, right?
Like, we eat lunch with three of us,
Kyou included, often, but...
R-Right...
It's not that I'm saying I don't like you.
More like, I wasn't really looking to get in a relationship with you.
Wait, I guess that was rude of me.
If that's fine with you,
do you want to give dating a try?
We're both going to get to know each other a bit at a time, right?
Then, I thought it's not so bad to spend that time as boyfriend and girlfriend, not just as friends.
Then...
You're my girlfriend starting now. Sound good?
H-Hey...
I'm sorry... I can't stop my tears...
It's as if I'm dreaming.
I'm so happy...
It's unbelievable.
Another World
Kyou Arc
Oh. You're trying to go to nursing school?
Yes, it's been my dream since I was little.
I haven't thought about my future at all.
Um, I don't think you need to rush.
I think I do.
If I sit around doing nothing,
even you might get fed up with me.
That's impossible!
No matter what happens, I won't get fed up with you!
Thanks.
Nobody's ever said anything like that to me before.
So I'm a little touched.
It's nothing...
Hey, Kyou!
What are you doing on a Sunday?
You have to spend time with Ryou.
Mind your own business, you idiot.
Yeah, I guess. Sorry.
Don't be.
You know.
She's liked you since she was a junior.
Really?
So? You think you two will get along fine?
I think so.
She's diligent and kind, but blushes really easily, so I have to make sure I take it easy with her.
Yeah, exactly!
But that's also what's cute about her.
What?
No, I was just thinking you really watch out for your sister.
Not really.
Forget it.
Hey.
Have you kissed Ryou yet?
Huh?!
O-Of course I haven't!
Come on! You have to lead her more.
Even if you say that, this is my first time dating a girl.
Then do you want to practice?
Practice kissing.
With me.
Think of me as Ryou.
We are twins, so we look alike, right?
Yeah?
That's enough!
It's practice, so we can't really do it.
R-Right.
By any chance, were you taking it seriously?
Of course not, you idiot.
I'd say that was a six out of ten.
Yeah, yeah.
See ya.
Yeah.
In that park.
Seriously? Okazaki as in that delinquent?
Ah, those two.
They used to be in the same class. And they still look pretty close.
But-
Wow, he's here!
Keep it down, stupid.
Why do it at a place like that?
Isn't he embarrassed?
Yeah.
What are they all talking about?
'Morning, Okazaki!
What, even you?
What?! Me and Kyou?
Everyone at school knows about it.
That you were kissing Kyou yesterday.
Oh. How should I explain that...
It's not what everyone thinks.
Don't play dumb with me.
I knew something was going on.
You looked like you were having fun.
I'm saying nothing happened.
Besides, I'm dating the younger sister.
You and Fujibayashi Ryou?
Seriously?
Is it that big of a surprise?
Well, you guys are complete opposites of each other.
On the other hand, I can imagine you dating Kyou.
Don't come up with things on your own!
Hey, does Fujibayashi know about this?
I bet she'll hear it when she comes to school whether she likes it or not.
Ah, there you are.
Hey.
Come with me for a sec.
I won't take up too much of your time.
I haven't done anything yet!
Hey, Kyou!
You-
You know, I seriously can't believe it.
Why not? Is what I'm saying that strange?
More like, I never sensed anything like that between us.
Is it one of those things you don't notice because you were too close?
Yeah, maybe it's something like that.
Hey, you want me to show you very simple proof?
W-Wait a minute!
This is strange. Are you sure you like me?
What do you mean?
I'm sorry if I'm wrong,
but you like Okazaki, don't you?
W-What are you saying?
I... I'm...
She tried to go out with me to
get rid of that rumor of you and her.
Who cares about rumors?
If it were just an ordinary rumor, I don't think she'd go this far.
You're late.
Hey, don't take what Youhei said seriously.
Seeing you and Ryou so close,
I felt like wanting a boyfriend, too.
So I thought I'd pick Youhei.
Then-
Stop it!
Do you go fishing for guys on a whim like that?
Mind your own business.
You should only think about Ryou.
Okay?
You can't make your girlfriend worry about you.
See ya.
That'll be ¥800.
Tomoya-kun.
I wanted to try calling you by your first name.
You didn't like it?
Of course not.
Really?
Yeah. Kyou always calls me by-
You're right. You're thinking, "why now".
Yeah.
If you don't mind, could you call me "Ryou", as well?
Then, Ryou.
T-Tomoya-kun.
I'll see you again.
Yeah.
Tomoya-kun!
I'll see you tomorrow.
I guess I'll stop by Sunohara's place.
Botan!
Puhi.
What's wrong? It's Sunday today, so nobody's here.
Hey!
Botan! Wait!
Kyou.
What's wrong?
N-Nothing's wrong.
What about you? Weren't you on a date with Ryou?
You're soaking wet.
Don't come.
Please.
Y-you should only think about Ryou.
Since, after all, you're Ryou's boyfriend.
That's got nothing to do with this right now.
You'll catch cold.
I said don't come!
You have to leave me alone!
Don't bother with me anymore...
Kyou!
Stop it!
Hey.
S... Stop it.
Stop being kind to me.
I'm an idiot...
...so if you act kind to me, I'll get the wrong idea.
I was afraid.
I was afraid to ask you out.
If I had asked you out and gotten rejected,
we might not even have been able to stay friends.
Even if I'd gotten to go out with you, Ryou would have become sad.
Then, it was best that I gave up.
I thought that would be the best for everyone!
Yet... now, I'm feel nothing but regret.
I'm such an idiot.
It's something I chose, and yet...
Kyou, I'm-
Tomoya.
I'm Fujibayashi Kyou.
I'm not Ryou.
I was too late.
Bye bye.
Well, I guess it's a complicated matter.
All of this with twins.
What would you do?
If I were in your shoes?
Make them both mine. No questions asked.
Can I punch you until you stop moving?
I'm sorry. I was joking.
Honestly, it's a big hassle.
If this is what I have to face...
You're right.
If you want to keep your distance from both of them now,
then that's the loser's way out.
You're trying to stay unscarred, aren't you?
If you've come this far, you'll have to hurt someone.
The more time you take to decide, the deeper and more it'll hurt.
For all three of you.
Yeah.
By the way, can I say one more thing?
People'd kill to have your problem!
Ow.
All right, time for lunch.
Tomoya-kun.
What did you need to talk about?
It's just the two of us, isn't it?
In manga, when it comes to being alone in a classroom after school, we usually see a kiss scene, don't we?
Fujibayashi.
Why are you calling me by my last name?
I always wanted to beat Onee-chan.
I didn't want to lose to her.
I knew who Onee-chan always had her eye on.
I asked for her advice, knowing her feelings.
I told her I wanted to get close with Tomoya-kun.
She was surprised, but smiled right after.
She said, "Leave it to me."
I knew she'd say that.
I knew I was being dirty, too.
Even then... Even then, I wanted to be near you.
Can't I replace Onee-chan?
I'll become more outgoing like Onee-chan.
I'll grow out my hair and practice cooking, too.
I will become the girl you wish for.
No.
It's not like that.
I don't want you to do something like that.
I want to be close to you.
I-
Okay, next problem.
Fujibayashi.
I guess she's not here.
Then Suzuki.
You're not going home?
The days I spent with you were a lot of fun.
I realized for the first time that it makes me so happy to be needed by others.
I thought I'd get along well with you like this.
But I can't.
I was being a jerk.
While I was with you, I was looking at someone else.
I kept it to myself even after realizing that.
I was taking advantage of your kindness...
I...
The person I love is...
...is your sister.
I'm sorry.
Tomoya.
Kyou!
Why did you...
Your hair!
She yelled at me.
Ryou told me not to run away.
I didn't mind if it stayed this way.
The place changes and goes. Like a wind, like clouds,
I didn't want to choose you if it meant hurting Ryou.
But she said it.
Like the traces of the heart, no halt at the places.
"That's impossible."
"It's too late."
"If you really love Tomoya, you can't run away anymore."
"There's no other choice but for both of us to get hurt."
The place is so far away be far apart.
"We ended up loving the same person."
I bet she's crying right now.
People's hand does not reach, so merely has the worship.
Really, we're so late.
Realizing, acting as though not realizing, and facing each other, too.
But I'll make this the last time we get hurt.
The place is a lofty lord, can't meet nobody put on.
Her, me, and you, too.
We will lose the place, so lofty which changes.
Yeah.
I love you, Tomoya.
I've... I've...
...always loved you.
Not all were desired. However, we're never sad.
Please don't apologize.
Still, there is still the place. Far away. Far away.
But...
If you apologize and I accept your apology, it'll feel like all of this was a joke.
I want to make those times a memory.
All the fun times.
All the hard times.
All of them.
So please, don't apologize.
Okay.
Thank you.
Where were we going tomorrow?
We said we'd go somewhere, right?
Ah, sorry. Cancel that.
The place buried in deep snow. Like the collapsing castle.
Ryou came and said let's go shopping.
So no can go with you.
I guess I don't have a choice.
Like the head of the shade, figure will be thrown away.
Yup. There's nothing you can do.
It's really been hot these days, hasn't it?
Yeah.
Hey. Was I really the right choice?
The hut buried in deep snow. It sinks in to the flood.
Huh?
Are you sure you're not thinking it was more comfortable being with Ryou?
Hey. I'll get mad.
Yes. Please get mad.
And the 'not dyeing' is dyed out, and waits for a oppose one.
Then I'll rest easy.
Isn't something wrong there?
Then let's make it simple.
H-Hey!
Tomoya.
I love you.
Summer's coming, isn't it?
Yeah.